fifth and last but by no means least as
far as he's concerned anyway we can't
bend Eddy of Italy so before we get
underway we've had a question for one of
our punters by Twitter and thank you to
all the people who have contacted both
Leon and myself on Twitter about the
spray onto the surface of the diving
people could you explain please sir yes
I could so just on the other side of the
flowers there what you're seeing is
ripples on the surface of the water now
they're caused by well what can best be
described as hose pipes pointing in from
the side of the of the diving pool now
this the intention behind this is just
to disturb there we are the sprays well
done thanks very much director look at
that the spray coming there just to the
right of screen is actually disturbing
the water the reason for this is the
divers need to know exactly where the
surface of the water is if there are no
sprays the water becomes very very still
and you focus on the bottom of the
diving pool which is of course another
five point eight meters away from the
surface so the divers need to be very
precise when they're going to grab their
hands and punch that hole in the water
and the ripples there ensure the divers
can make that judgement correctly most
of the time well that's the problem
anyway I hopefully resolved for them
today with that spray onto the surface
hope that has answer the question which
a few people have posed to us time to
get underway with the first of the
twenty nine divers six rounds remember
five rounds with the women six round
with the men and the opening diver will
be Ethan warrant from Australia and
three point zero degree of difficulty in
the pike position to start off with is
his back two and a half somersaults
they little bit of splash being thrown
up there you could just see the
Australian front in there you know you
know agreeing with me beautiful take off
I was tricky opening up the contest 3.0
only she asked over a little bit of her
to go see the splash being thrown up
it's only gonna get 7z that needs to be
diving a little bit better than that to
put some pressure on these guys he's an
exceptional performer let's wait and see
my favorite number number 63 gets back
again
three sevens times three we've had that
a lot in the women's I presume we're
getting quite a few time in the men's as
well
63 for Warren now Damien Sealy of France
in were 2 and our summer saucer we've
been a splash here just a little bit but
you'd be surprised how exceptional this
guy is yes he is super bulky I think he
just needs to look at weights in order
to to gain muscle size incredible but
look at the power he generates inward
two and a half way above the diving
board effortless dive just making a
little bit of a mistake on the entry
into the water there
it'll get mid-60s but in the men's
competition you want to be sailing over
70 and even into the 80s to ensure
qualification so Damien Sealy is opening
dive produces sixty seven point five
zero remember three marks that you see
without a line through them are the ones
that count and you'll multiply that by
the degree of difficulty 3.0 on that
occasion onto the first of the Chinese
comes perch on back two and a half
summer sorts with Pike 3.0 and I'm
usually the Chinese separated by quite
some way so wait until way into the
contest before you see a second here
comes the first of Chinese the world
champion
yep he's a defending Olympic champion
also and looking in fine form here only
25 years old but already Olympic
champion four years ago and he'll be
looking to retain his title tomorrow
night but he still has to get look how
easy does that dive feet pointing Diane
this will get eight and a half it's not
as good as I've seen him do it but just
showing his pure class well as the
marker for everybody else to follow in
round one eight and an eight point five
times three just having a quick scowl at
his coach give him what for tell me Mary
can improve and I'm sure he knows
exactly what he has to do in with three
and a half somersaults we're talking
we're going for a big starter here
because that's off three point four
degree of difficulty for his opener and
it's a beauty as well Wow
so giverny is not going to give anything
away today he is D deed up to the max
look at that tape or down is back we're
talk more about that later not quite
sure how much of a benefit it is
obviously it's not affecting his dive
because that's three point four degree
of difficulty inward standing backwards
spinning forward that's a monster start
three look at that eighty-one that's why
I call brave we see more in the women
some people go over to point seven two
point eight he's gone in there straight
away saying I'm gonna make a statement
here and here comes a big dive straight
on would you believe that's one of his
easier dives three point four exciting
down a notch but not by much to Daniel
Arroyo of Mexico three point three on
this reverse two and a half one and a
half twists oh my goodness he's a little
bit close to the diving board there
you'll see on the replay his Tootsie's
come a little bit too close for comfort
for me look at this leaning over the
diving board squeezing into the fight
shape there he doesn't really want to be
any closer than that losing the control
of the dive as he goes into the water oh
this is the aerial shot all these all
right calm down calm down the judges
should penalize I wouldn't give him more
than a five or a five point five for
that and we got two injuries
down there Daniel Arroyo 61 point zero
five and they're near pedicure
Stephane feck of Germany to our Irish
viewers are enjoying that pronunciation
it's correct Fe CK is his surname back
two and a half somersaults with bike 3.0
degree of difficulty so we've come for
three point four to three point three
and back to normality if you like this
pike dive for stiff and thick it needed
to be good and I think that there's a
little bit off the mark for Stefan
normally a very very solid diver two
Germans in this Stefan the first one
here we are backward two and a half in
the pike position just bending at the
hips good Pike shape looks good till
they're just short of vertical landing
short as he goes in it's only gonna get
seven in half and I won't score over
seventy points and a lower degree of
difficulty needs to be nailed work to do
for Stefan feeling their way into the
competition and Stefan affect seven
point five across the board x 360 7.50 I
say would give me a diving and a math
lesson at the same time get value from
us don't you now to chop or Venezuela
height position for this inward two and
a half well steady start from the
Venezuela in his first Olympic Games
only 21 years old and if he continues to
dive out that I'm sure would be very
happy and watch him in training a little
bit hit-and-miss this is one of his
better dives straight up and down he
needs to be a safe distance from the
diving board which he is in word
spinning forwards yeah it's technically
proficient and it's reasonable diver
seven-and-a-half probably eight maybe
let's see
well entering enough we've gone from the
63s to the 67.5 being the current
currency for a lot of the dynastar see a
fourth mark of 67.5 we've seen today
see our Castro our Brazil for two and a
half with one twist no it's beautifully
executed it's a very easy die though
lots of the divers
to use the more complicated twisting
dives say so here a lot of the girls use
this dive not taking a turn away from
the way says our cruise does that dive I
still think he could add another twist
you see a lot of divers doing a double
twist here says I'll just going for the
single twist maybe later in his program
yeah he does use the forward two and a
half two twists later in his program so
starting easy it was paid off for him
though seventy three point five decent
start for the Brazilian puts him in
equals second place now this man hasn't
Olympics for 12 years can the young oh
well done Kenny twenty nine years old
used to divert gates in myself and he is
certainly gonna be relying on that
wealth of experience of international
competition to see him through this
Paula Murray he's a very neat and tidy
diver should sneak over some points for
that one little bit of splash as he goes
in good board timing it's got Chinese
coaches to look after him or to put him
through his paces at his home in
Malaysia and here he is feeling seventy
1.30 yes mentioning he he was involved
in the diving competition in 2000 Sydney
hasn't competed at the Olympics since
his first Olympics in four for the
Malaysian now the second of the Germans
here's Patrick housing back two and a
half somersaults with Mike for his
opening gambit here's one to watch well
what a dive you're looking for the
vertical entry into the water and with
no splash that's exactly what the judges
are looking for
and that's exactly what Patrick is
delivered on his first round dive if he
gets over 70 points he keeps himself
well within the mix this is only 3.0 so
it needs to be good and it is just that
yeah I think it'd be happy with the
return on that all 872 for Patrick
housing give me a kiss to the friends
and family back home give them here I
think a lot of people in Europe
certainly have made the journey over to
London to support their divers and quite
a few for North America as well now from
the Ukraine here's Alexei trigger off in
with
the girls not messing around either he's
coming out all guns blazing it's a game
of tactics actually if you come out with
a big degree of difficulty which is
exactly what he's doing here and in word
three and a half we've seen one already
and he's nailed that one that's going to
get 83.4 degree of difficulties could
have put him high up on the leaderboard
speaking of boards he's not wise a safe
distance away from the diving board I
know lots of you at home like gasp every
time a diver comes near that's pretty
safe just 81 good good opening dive yeah
goes level with Kuznetsov of Russia that
opening dive now Xavier Garcia looking
to reach the semi-finals for the first
time always been knocked out in the
prelims both Beijing and in Athens back
two and a half for him to start with
well it's a good start from Xavier yeah
third Olympic Games he'll be looking to
progress further he's in good shape he's
been working hard so what can he do
today let's his opening dive his easiest
one little bit of discrepancy as you
went in though he should sneak seven and
a half's maybe even a couple of eights
sometimes a bit of a shaky start let's
see how he goes on with the rest of his
program
yeah judges concur with Leon 7.5 across
the board I'll give him a total just
outside top placings in 7th place now on
to the American and Chris Cole well
ain't that the champs in Rome back in
2009 9th here in February at the
competition that took place in this very
pool back to an hour some sorts with
Pike opening gambit for Cole Oh sneaky
it was nice looked like he was gonna
over rotate as he went in but very
cleverly saves the dive by bending
arching through the back bend in the
knees giving the impression that he's
completely vertical so a superb start
there for core well obviously knowing
exactly where he is in the air when
you're spinning backwards you could only
ever see where you've been so you have
to judge when to let go and Chris
showing his experience here 27 years old
and he got that down alright remember
just the top 18 from 29 started will go
through good opening gambit by Crisco or
72 for him
joins Patrick housing on that score to
mature or hace or France
oh nice very nice indeed it's a big dive
to start with and it's a tough one too
it's only three point three I personally
think you should be worth more than this
you're standing backwards he goes
swinging the arms one and a half twist
two and a half somersaults Wow and he
just a fantastic job on that entry
that's gonna put him top of the pile or
near his damn what a tie from the young
Frenchman well Jesse I'm finding it hard
to compute as a still waiting first
quarter comes through as you watch
another replay look at them spreading
the air right there with his hands and
causing that suction and the rip entry
looking at schools as the biggest so far
eighty four point one five for the
Frenchman can be delighted with that had
a very very good string of performances
in Shanghai last year I think it was
surprised to everybody now the young
Canadian Francois in Bordeaux Lackey
okay for 3.0 to open his campaign in
wood two and a half somersaults with
pike
yeah it's neat and tidy little bit maybe
lacking a little bit of strength on his
takeoff there some of the other divers
completing the dive more easily than
Francois squeezing into that Pike shape
if you just see there he didn't really
have a lot of drop time but it's still
straight up and down and you'll get
close to 70 points only 21 years old
first Olympic Games I've not seen him
dive before
69 for him this question is a bit of
facial hair there
swimmers tend to take everything off
body hair leg hair facial hair it's a
precursor for a good dive or not well as
long as you're impressing the judges
with your good looks that's all that
matters
that's why you didn't do any better than
you did Ilya Zakharov now with an inward
three and a half somersault we took
three point four degree of difficulty on
this yep Zakhar off is not messing
around either he's talked of any earlier
on in the vines and these boys are doing
their beach weights at home and they're
flexing their muscles today these are
big dives nowhere to go Wow cruising
that already complete competed here at
these games and he's gonna be strong
today this is going to get well over 80
points superb opening round dive to the
lead who is a lead by some way by five
points he's just checking on the scores
now just ahead of Ross 8 by a couple of
points but it is the lead for zakharov
eighty six point seven zero that's an
impressive way to start now he's a man
who a few weeks ago didn't even know if
he would be here or not explain why
after we've seen the first dive from
Alexandre de Partie it's a back two and
a half somersaults with Pike yeah Jesus
tipping over as he goes into the water
as you could imagine Alex with his
wealth of experience two Olympic medals
from the previous two games in this
event both of them silver technically
absolutely super many young divers
around the world watching this you
wouldn't go far wrong looking at
Alexander day parties technique but
everyone can make those slight errors of
judgment and Alex jurors tipping over a
vertical as he punches a hole here look
at that super slow-mo showing the air
being sucked
with the diver into the water now why
was the almost not here because he hit
his head on the diving board in
spectacular fashion in Rome a few weeks
before later on there was a real
question mark over as to whether he'd be
here or not he is here he is competing
as is Ilya Kovalchuk he's going for the
big dive to start with in the Tuck
position I should nails it as well now
I'm interested I'm interested to observe
and to watch the game of tactics being
played by both Russian divers and both
the Ukrainian divers all of them opting
for this opening dive which is tricky
it's complicated it's three point four
and if you get it right it puts you
straight up in the business end of the
field from vine 1 now what does that do
to your competitors when they're trying
to catch up I think it's a game of
tactics being well played yeah though
not quite as well executed as some
previous ones but still a decent mark as
it would be with the 3.4 degree of
difficulty seventy six point five zero
for kavaja yes Sebastian Gaston either
Colombia two and a half oh it's a nice
dive very precise you can see the
difference between the image three and a
half and the inward two and a half in
with three and a half there's a lot of
spins to get in the two and a half
opting for the pike position it's a lot
slow rotation it's very well placed but
when the guys are slotting in those big
big big degrees of difficulty you're
gonna be very hard to keep up with them
with such low degree of difficulty well
let's see what he has in the resumes
program to play catch-up cuz that's what
I have to do after that 72 for the
Colombian the big cheer greeting at the
arrival of the first of the two British
divers today and hopefully like we've
seen previous British divers do he'll
soak up some of the atmosphere before he
gets involved in his opening dive feel
be moving a weight from the end of the
diving board it's our back two and a
half sour sauce with pike Chris Meers
with Jack lure to come in a couple of
divers time 3.0 degree of difficulty in
the pike position
you're a superb start for the first of
team GP there's his mum and dad I've
obviously seen him compete already in
the 3-meter synchronized springboard
fantastic job coming fifth in that event
beautiful elevation squeezing into the
pike shape all-important entry into the
water tipping over a little bit nice
steady start from Chris Meers only 19
little better on the entry let's see
what the hearts for the judges maybe
seven point five six seven point five
zero Chris Meers reasonable start though
for him puts him in the decent order
Malaysia for three and a half oh it's
steady it's on his head little bit short
as he went into the water which is a
real shame this guy hates me but when he
was from China
now he's coaching in Malaysia and now
he's allowed to compete for them so he's
see the grand old age of 30 years old
but he still got it pretty good seven
7.5 maybe there could be a little bit
off the pace today marks are yeah 7.5 2
of them and a 7 so he opens up with a
total of 60 8.20
now great cheer to greet Jack lure from
a European Junior Champion made the
final in Shanghai last year and
acquitted himself very well indeed in
with two and a half somersaults 3.0 not
too high tariffs to so low for that
comes up later for Jack yeah he's been
diving well in training he won't be so
pleased without entry into the water
he's playing safe a little bit here Jack
does through the inward three and a half
but playing a game of tactics here
opening with her easier in which enough
he absolutely cruises it just come out a
little bit too early though the water
brushing gets the front side of his body
he's only going to get 7.5 that will put
him a little bit off the pace but I'm
very confident having watched him in
training that he will feature as we go
on
yeah reasonable opening offer from Jack
66 again 7.5 s and a 7 will count all
those marks with the line struck through
will not count remember none of these
marks carry through to the semis which
we on Tuesday morning local time now to
Stefano's a Patronus from greece oh it's
the finest probably one of the weakest
divers in this contest he's gonna really
need to be on the top of his game to
carry on through he's one of the the
younger generation of Greek divers so 22
years old it did very very well to make
these top 29 you were here today just
you see over vertical
just staying in his shape a little bit
too long as he goes into the water you
can see the splash moving away legs
coming apart a little bit he'll get
penalized for that there we go
why heavily so as well sixes from him
fifty four point zero zero if it gets
bored he loves reading his back Tomas or
Rinaldi next up for Italy and two
Italians are late in the program last of
the divers will be from Italy inward two
and a half somersaults height position
difficulty three points here and another
quite hirsute Italian today well it
looked a little bit like to the diving
boards he's always tricky getting the
distance correct on this inward movement
you're standing backwards on your
tiptoes you then need to swing your arms
jump up and away but spin forwards
towards the diving board he's okay I did
move back a little bit but he's okay
throwing up a little bit of splash shame
really
7.5 s incoming I would imagine gotta
give it the clap
seven point five and seven before
Renaldi and that's okay
not a bad start for him chin Kai for
China again just easing his way into the
program no big starter for him back two
and a half somersaults from the pike
position yet maybe the same as as he
Chong / Chong just playing a little bit
safe 3.0 to start the program I've seen
it much better than this in training
it's much better this is actually well
dare I say for the Chinese standard for
King Kai standard mediocre I wouldn't
give that more than an eighth maybe I'll
sneak 8.5 because of his distinguished
career and results previous results list
a little bit sure to vertical it is very
precise let's see what the judges seek
higher than I thought seventy six point
five zero we have said before they don't
we'll say again the Chinese invariably
are marked up on their dives because of
their reputations maybe that was a case
in the case in point there Troy do mate
will go with three point one so kind of
betwixt in between in terms of the
tariffs here on a forward three and a
half seller sorts with pike second of
the Americans to compete to think Oh
superb Troy the oldest competitor in
this contest as its coach Mack Scogin an
Olympian himself and absolutely drills
the entry let's check this out here we
go forward three and a half somersaults
in the pike position now you see me now
you don't what an entry this should get
the first nines of the contest and quite
right to Troy you know achieving a
lifetime dream of winning Olympic medal
earlier in the week and Wow well the
Americans are having a very good week I
think inspired by the fact that Greg
Louganis is here to mentor them and to
help them through and it seems to be
working dividends so of course the week
he goes into third place Troy to mate
after that time yeah Castillo welter as
it is on our sheet of paper here with a
forward two and a half somersaults two
twists pike three point four big one
or the crowd like that one as you could
imagine some winning arming it's a
pretty good dive for me out I taught you
through it as we go into the replay
hurdle set on the end little we're back
from the end here's one and a half
somersaults here's the double twist
super quick on the double twist yells
offs
normally all taped up he has terrible
problems with ankle injuries but today
he looks apart from some on his toes he
looks tape free which is a good sign
because this guy is an exciting diver
and when he's on he's on and he's on
joint first after that degree of
difficulty helping him up to a total of
eighty six point seven zero up there
with zakharov frankini get going here is
Robert Rodriguez or Venezuela he's done
okay on the entry into the water
probably a little recive as he went in
so ankle heavily strapped there these
guys on the springboard putting
themselves through their paces often
receive injuries to all different parts
of their body but the ankles do take a
kicking you looking to get really really
strong legs just skipping back from the
diamond board they're a little bit
aggressive on the way in see what judges
think were they're gonna give him my
favorite mark of 63 all the sevens times
three and that's how you arrive at the
total score for him 25th place at the
moment cause top 18 go through and last
of the divers in round one is another of
the Italians just those muscles McKinney
Benedetti
and we're two-and-a-half with Mike Oh
beautiful tie from the Italian to finish
up vine one Mickey missed out in Athens
didn't make the Italian team and then
again in Beijing it all looked good and
then he missed that again so this was
going to be his last-ditch effort to
make the games he was absolutely
thrilled to be on the team and that's
opening up his campaign in fine style
indeed rotten mickey Oh Mickey you're so
fine you're so fine you blow my mind hey
mickey 8.0 total arm 72
for Mikayla Ben Bethy and of round one
and what a competitive round it was if
that's only the prelims and is what the
same isn't the final gonna be like quota
and zakharov joint top looking their way
around down the board a great start for
Mattie Ross a in third place
all of those will become to be through
we stop right now as indeed most of them
on this page will be by down to the
Malaysian in 18th as yet no sign of the
Brits you have to wait for page number
three for them but sixty eight point two
is a qualification place and sixty seven
point five zero for Chris Meers 66 for
Jack lore and at the bottom was two
follows Petronas probably won't be
thinking about can we map from the
semi-finals at this stage but there's
still time to make up and repair the
damage great crowd in here again and the
Aquatic Centre for the diving very few
spare seats seventeen and a half
thousand or there abouts crammed in here
for every session of the diving and here
to support just the Brits but also the
world wide divers as well like the
Australian Ethan warrant Australian seen
a bit of a boost at the moment after the
week they've had in the Aquatic Centre
for three and a half summer sorts with
Pike 3.1 for his first second round dive
for his first second round dive that's
right yeah are you flew me a little bit
there I think you through Ethan ever so
slightly as well a little bit of a shaky
start first round second round a little
bit off the mark
just marginally but then diving comes
down to my G's short as he went in short
vertical it is still getting seven and a
half maybe squeezing an eighth but I've
seen Ethan diving better than this just
letting go of his legs a little bit
ambitiously a little bit early but yeah
I think there might be as parrots there
yeah just to clarify he is only doing
one second round dive and that was it
seventy two point eight five no
repechage here or anything in dive you
know get a second chance come back again
and same round Damien Sealy of France
19th after round one
this is a diamond competition in case
you think you have gone to the
bodybuilding exercises in with three and
a half service or we took 3.4 big degree
of difficulty I super-strong well you
can see how strong he is but he manages
to use the board very well 3-meter
springboard slot about rhythm timing
coordination strength power dynamic
explosive nature anyway he's got it all
going on he does make a little bit of a
botch on the end which is a real shame
he did all the hard work and then he
seems to go loose in there in his body
as he went into the water look at this
super slow motion see the dive is part
in their hands as they're trying to
escape into the water with absolutely no
splash it almost gets away with it
but not quite seventh and 6.5 where the
others discarded so total or when you
multiply it by the degree of difficulty
is 68 for him I'm smoking too many
mistakes from the man in ninth place
after round 1 a Chong of China world
champion Olympic champion three World
Series wins this year under his belt
forward two and a half seven salts and
two twists in the pipe position whoa
indeed the crowd a ruin and yesterday as
he addresses as soon as he goes in there
certainly no suit catastrophe as he went
in the water beautiful dive look how
high his way above the five meter
forward two and a half two twists he
makes it looks like it's a walk in the
park and I can assure you this is no
walk in the park this is that one of the
toughest dives that you can perform and
her Cheung just makes it look like it's
a beginner dive it makes makes it look
easy you could do that Bob oh yeah well
funny I was doing earlier today but they
didn't give me in the top 29-cent they
just missed out her Chong with eight
point five sand nines and the briefest
of reefs there is a mark suspense just
up the way in case he runs out of
underwear afghani Kuznets off where they
back three and a half summer suppose we
talk Wow we up to three point five this
is upping the stakes somewhat oh wow I
don't know what to say you give any is
coming out and he's got nowhere to hide
in fact none of his competitors have got
any way to
Jimmy carries on like this he's going to
be tough to keep up with even the two
chinese divers three point five and he's
buried it that's really good he'll get
or high 70s and i think he can do it
even better than that
lots of taping down his back but
obviously holding him together
goodbye afghan he's coming out there's a
revelation for you 77 for the russian
which puts him in second place daniel a
royal of mexico high tariffs dives here
three point five followed by a three
point four four two and a half
somersaults two twists in the pike
position almost got it down little bit
short as he went into the water
lots to fit in in this dive we've
already seen it from her chong just
earlier in the vines who absolutely
cruised it Daniel just showing us how
difficult it is Lance on the ending good
time double twist one and a half just
about scrapes it in it's good those high
degree of difficulty or get him over 70
points Wow and even the lower end of the
field are diving well again there are
some amazing performances today and some
amazing dives and that was not bad not
quite in the 8th range but seven point
five and a seven James get on with it
for three and a half here you go the
first calamity oh oh my goodness it's
silent in here sorry about that
I think he's okay I can talk you through
it what happened he landed on the end of
the diving board and his foot completely
slipped off the side he probably lost a
toenail or two there and therefore
completely look at this slips off the
side of the board doesn't get in his
flight ship only has hold of one later
looked a bit like the Isle of Man and
then absolutely smacks himself like he'd
just been slammed in wrestling he'll die
motocross support Stefan feck is out of
here yeah he will not be back tomorrow
because there's no marks attributed to
that dive because he didn't complete the
dive on to job Fitness waiter Oh yet
exactly the same time he just watched
his German counterpart there absolute
well it doesn't happen very often but he
just yeah
really feel for him anyway the
competition goes on there's still places
to be fought for and this young man he's
trying to keep his head keep his call
other divers will be aware of that
calamity that just took place with
Stefan there and he's certainly out of
it but this guy he's still in it the
venezuelan well that's the kind of mark
the Stefan effect wouldn't like to have
seen against his name rather zero zero
zero zero sixty eight point two zero it
is on that particular occasion Cesar
Castro our Brazil forward three and a
half with pike yet very tidy fun stays
up opened up with that beautiful first
round dive lower degree of difficulty
slowly starting to build now three point
one this one we've seen the previous
three divers do this one squeezing into
the pike shape just bending forward from
the hip keeping the legs straight he's
tired he maybe lose his feet a little
bit as he goes in there this look at
eight keep him in the mix it is gonna be
so tight for those top 18 places I tell
you already it's developing into a
contest where there will be few marks
separating the time is around the 15 to
20 mark kimi yo oh it's good
probably needed to come mind a little
bit more on the dive there to give the
impression of being completely vertical
aerial work is good here we are
squeezing into the pike out here's the
double twist maybe out a little bit
early leaving himself a little bit to do
marginally short but that look at eight
if you get an eight you're gonna go
close to 80 points and if you're on 80
points that's where exactly you need to
be eighty one point six zero to be
precise weaken the yoke and that will
help his charge up the table quite a bit
he's in third place now binder Chong and
Kuznetsov Patrick housing hopes the same
fate won't befall him as his German
teammate
oh it's a good dive now maybe the judges
will see this or maybe it's just for us
on the replay I think Patrick was a
little bit twisted as he went in landed
on the corner of the diving board still
manages to do a good job you can see his
head there just looking everywhere every
summer stop but I could see both feet as
he goes in which means he's a little bit
over twisted penny judges give him less
than a seven they would have seen that
but of course the judges do not get the
replay no they've missed it lucky yeah
it got away with that one and because of
it
he's got seventy two point eight five
which will put him in the top five I
likes a plug or off of Ukraine three
point eight stand by forward four and a
half somersaults Oh stand by hold on
take your hats off he did very well
indeed they're the hurdle step the
approach to the end didn't do him any
favors he had one foot slightly off the
side of the board this is three point
eight and he sneaks it in nicely you'll
get seventh on that look at where he
lands and then he shoots forward that's
way too far away from the diving board
but wow what a diver to be able to
control that when your takeoff is medium
too poor Wow
good work three point eight those marks
along the bottom which is not allowing
on the screen for very long sorry we
can't take it all in but eighty three
point six it was we go on to Garcia yeah
good work from javi not waiting around
not giving us any time to go too much
into the detail they see these dives are
so difficult I don't know where to start
all he did lose his legs a little bit
there that's very clear on the replay
you probably wouldn't see that when you
watch it for the first time double twist
super slo-mo cam just showing the
strains on the divers lots of photos on
the internet of divers faces close-up
mid dive the slow-motion giving you an
impression that's good from javi
and 70 6.50 smile on the face of Crisco
well I said I was really enjoying
themselves here enjoying themselves in
competition I'm mostly hoping that they
go e returning for the semi files in
about 14 hours time for three and a half
somersaults with pike if a go well 3.1
degree of difficulty have a mere
Bagatelle compared to that 3.8 yea 3.1
but if you're going to execute it with
that much precision it's going to work
for you Cristie nips and their buns
medalist in the three metre synchro
supporting his teammate here Chris doing
a beautiful job quite tall for a dive up
so he looks very elegant as he's
spinning around in the shapes a little
back from the end but that's straight up
and down that'll get or eight eight and
a half's good it's a good dive yeah
anything in the mid 70s and high up is a
good dive and that's when he gets
seventy five point nine five a core well
now we had an impressive start from
mto row say ah
France can he back it up three point
four degree of difficulty on this inward
three and a half summer sorts with tuck
he can't back it up I think you just
piled that well the commentators curse
right there Bob
opening round dive put him in the top
what top four
where was he after the first round
incredible now just showing you how
difficult these dives are very easy to
get lost get confused spinning around so
quickly your eyes are being pulled back
loads of g-forces
what a shame because the aerial work was
fantastic and Oh see ya yeah has a chat
with his coach but you can't get that
one back I'm afraid fours and 4.5 that
really has dented his chances are
returning tomorrow but that first round
dive still has a decent chance Francois
in bull du Lac before Canada you got a
raw recruit reader Canadian diving four
or three and our service orts with pike
three point one the degree of difficulty
attached to this one
Royce ended up okay in the end I don't
know whether you saw the same thing as
me as he came into the end I wasn't sure
which direction he was gonna end up
facing it seemed to drift a little bit
in the air like it was windy anyway he
got it together in the end forward three
and a half Pike you know he's he's not
as dynamic or as strong as some of the
other divers so he's never gonna get
more than a 7 7.5 - he's not finishing
the dive high enough but still 21 years
old where was he going well going
sideways it did seem that way marks were
ok not overly impressive for him 60 5.10
that's gonna take a little bit of dent
in terms of his position in the table in
here zakharov back three and a half some
sorts 3.50
super smooth now these medals are going
to be highly contested and they've got a
long way to go yet but if you're a
betting man or lady and you're watching
this this guy is worth a punt beautiful
dive this is so tricky 3.5 that's going
to get way over 80 points Wow
he's putting the pressure on the Chinese
well he was second in Shanghai but the
Chinese last year because they were 1 in
3 and he was second in Shanghai and the
way started here you would not bet not
being in that position again 84 - very
solid Ives eighty six point seven and 84
to start with reversed two and a half
won a half twist examiner de Partie just
showing his skill landing way back from
the end of the diving board I shifted
back in my chair I wasn't happy look at
that way back from the end has to reach
up and over the diving board if he
wasn't so skilled he'd have been a lot
closer to the diving board there of
course a few weeks ago hitting his head
on the diving board on a different dive
- this one anyway safe distance away in
the end it's only gonna get seven and a
half's it's okay he's okay yeah 7.5 Alex
perhaps still not quite in the shape we
don't expect to see him in terms of his
quality of diving three point three
degree of difficulty on that so
helped him a little bit bit of a buffer
Ilya Vasa 3.8 dive again the big tariffs
early from the Ukraine and Russia Ford
four and a half oh nice nice very good
commercia Wow I wish I could describe to
you how difficult this dive actually is
because the two you've seen so far have
been absolutely spot on forward four and
a half hanging on to those shins bending
at the ankles and at the knees just
squeezing into that tight ball
this could get 90 points that's
absolutely stunning what a dive
obviously the tape helping I need to get
some tape on yeah you do but make sure
it's the right tape this time please
ninety one point two zero for kavaja he
goes into second place minders ekor off
and they really are front-loading their
dives here the high tariffs early on
giving them the early advantage yeah
he's looking to get rid of his dives not
get rid of them so I get them done very
very quickly as soon as the referee
gives you permission where you go
forward three and a half in the pike
position yeah it's it's tough to follow
such a big scoring dive it'll get sevens
I think sevens is going to cook it in
this kind of competition sevens it is
and that gives you a total of sixty five
point one zero forecast Anita just me is
enjoying its preamble Prelude if you
like his second round dive which is a
reverse two and a half somersaults with
Mike just on the cusp of qualification
after round one three more formal rounds
after this nice really really good I was
listening to the crowd of those Tom
Daley Sarah Barrow Peter Waterfield all
of them here to support their teammates
Chris Meers only 19 years old beautiful
reverse two-and-half needed it needs to
go over 70 points and that will holding
his nerves smiling enjoying this
occasion inspired by performances so far
into the hot tub to keep warm
and then straight back out into the
call-off area good go good good 3 8 72
he'll be happy with that and that will
move him up the table by a mark or two
in a position or two as well Malaysia
are back two and a half or just a little
bit off his game as short as he entered
the water every work was ok I think he
just came out of the dive a little bit
too ambitious Lee a little bit too early
we shall cost him you'll only get 7s
there we are just needed to hang on a
little bit longer than the water
wouldn't have smacked him on the back of
the legs as he went in there we go next
up Jack no I could already hear the
crowd shouting and cheering there's too
much low fourth Wong first and his total
as they take it off the screen for you
was 63 exactly now this man's hero is
Usain Bolt oh it's probably be by what
he saw on the track last night jack
pretty inspired looks a little shaky out
there for Jackie's got so much home
support yeah I've seen it better than
this he's right on the corner of the
diving board he does really well not to
end up in the middle of the pool doing a
Stephen feck but he manages to hang on
there even with a poor takeoff and look
at the strain and effort going into this
one and a half twist into the 1 and a
half to us into the two and a half
somersaults he squares it up nicely on
the end but that was a poor takeoff well
done jack staying with it sevens and 7.5
it's gonna put him right around the 18
on 19 position 29th and I played frayed
at the bottom and likely to remain there
unless things improved greatly mister
pentose a Patronus forward three and a
half Oh beautiful entry into the water
we're talking about the repente tree and
that was an ideal example of one
punching a water with a flat hand
ripping the hands aside as he goes here
I was causing a vacuum just disappear as
he went in could work from the young
Greek diver well of course he can't
village bottom because that will go to
Stefan feck after that failed dive so he
will have moved on position anyway
that's me I'll have a few positions
that's far up to 21st to phallus a
Patronus of greece i want to tomas over
in Aldie first of the two attacks I
think is done with that interruption so
thank you very much forward three and a
half somersaults with point three point
one the degree of difficulty tomasa
unfazed by the peculiar shouting coming
from an audience member
divers in as soon as the whistle is
blown by the referee that is the sign to
the audience to to keep stun and someone
decided to share it Tommaso unfazed by
it the dives okay it's why it's good
actually but in this level of
competition it goes down to okay seven
7.5 s yep sevens it will be times a
degree of difficulty three point one
those marks on your left with the line
struck through do not count towards the
total score sure you know that by now we
get new views all the time who need to
know that forward two and a half
somersaults two twists for Ching Kai of
China 3.4 degree of difficulty on this
it's very good it's tidy it's precise
chin kind not looking like him like he's
for myself I must admit the Russians are
certainly taking it to him and I think
that that might move him up a little bit
from 7th but not a whole lot it's good
it'll get 8 in fact it is a very good
dive for this first round I've left him
off the case a little bit off the pace
and off the case sure it's gonna be a
long competition it could be a very
brief case actually but they would be
alright for so many files I'm sure
alright for the finalists were 85 for
Ching Kai again maybe ever marked a
little bit there but that's the way the
judges saw it Troy do you may do a very
good start
can he back it up three point three
degree of difficulty on this reverse two
and a half somersaults 1/2 twists
formed in the pikey position unwavering
yes he can back it up yeah very very
solid all about consistency and Troy to
me is certainly displaying that out here
today obviously on a high for winning an
Olympic medal last week and so he should
be eight to eight point five s will it
get eighty points if it does he'll
certainly be very much up in the
business end of the field after round
two I think to clarify for you if you
saw the women's on the previous couple
of days then you may have seen five
rounds the women's is five the men's is
six so we'll be halfway at the end of
the next round round three round two
well into round two now
Hale guess deal well de Mexico in with
three and a half seven sorts would tuck
joint leader after the first round
yeah that's going to keep him certainly
in the top half of the field and that's
what it's all about this morning three
point four degree of difficulty yes
maybe moving his hips back a little bit
before he takes off so he's just a
little low on the water but you're
looking for that vertical entry and
anything close to 80 points is exactly
what you're looking for and I'm sure
y'all will be there yet they like it
though there are the coaches eighty one
point six zero and that will keep him
right close to the top if not quite at
the top anymore he's in second place
behind Kinnear zakharov is a Rodriguez
for three and a half going in the wrong
direction to start with he seemed to
place his first foot very close to the
end and then drift backwards that's
obviously a slight error but he manages
to look way back from the end of the
springboard that's not very springy back
there and you need to be right on the
end obviously not over the end we see
what happens when you know you've got
your feet over the end of the diving
board anyway Robert survives
let's see what marks again happier
worried again there that's what most
certain other calamity waiting to happen
6.5 s across the board sixty point four
five not going to help him a great deal
Kelly Ben Betty wants to go and he is
going oh it's beautiful entry into the
water a little bit of short vertical as
he goes in make you would ilanic wanted
to yeah he's warming up his legs to to
go that here we are here's the replay
squeezing into the Pike shape or just
crimping his knees slightly there to
make the rotations a little bit easier
that's actually a little bit off way
needs but he's right on the corner as
well it's so tricky as you're as a
springboard diver to to land on the end
of the diving board it seems this
evening they're going in all kinds of
directions are they like if they've all
been in the pub before this one I doubt
it very much so we put goose grease on
the end of the board or something
slipping off it's amazing what's
happened in this competition that's why
we already had two rounds and four more
still to come
Ilya Zakharov want to start from him
watch that boy he could be very very
dangerous indeed already is yeah el
castillo welter kavaja of ukraine
ukraine three and four USA five chinese
six and seven that's a surprise
Chris Meers a snuck into the top
eighteen as has Jack law so Jack loss
stays there in four rounds time he and
Chris Mears will be progressing into the
semi files these on the last page and
why they got too much to do or might as
well forget it including Stefan Peck
sadly is there what sixty points adrift
of everybody else after that failed
second round dive it's been a very
intriguing and entertaining competition
so far
if you need all the twists and turns
that we weren't expecting and the
Chinese further down the pecking order
that we had imagined that's because some
people have front loaded their dives
here with very big tariffs that's right
the Chinese still have their highest
degrees of difficulty still to come and
of course it's about six dives and not
two let's say third of the way through
big third round dive for Ethan Warren
it's a three point eight
Ward four-and-a-half lot of risk but on
all the points attached if he gets this
right oh yes
Wow seems to be the evening that
everyone is giving their forward four
and a half a good show and Ethan Warren
needed a good one little bit off the
pace after his first two times
this is his biggest dive his most
difficult dive and he certainly slots it
in beautifully 86 87 88 keep going
eighty nine point three zero and he was
19th after round two that will do him a
great deal of good
she won't quite a few places well now
Danny and Seeley
are France for three and a half quite as
big yeah opting for the slightly easier
forward so forward three and a half only
carries a three point one but it's much
less riskier than the three point eight
we saw previously salmon doing a good
job there lots of people asking on
Twitter why there's three diving boards
there well there's a lot of divers
competing and so when you've got you
know thirty girls and forty boys or
training at the same time to have three
diving boards to choose from actually
the easiest of congestion all the diving
boards are three metres they should all
be made at the same you know ingredients
so to speak or do reflect spring boards
so it's just divers preference sixty
nine point seven five for Damian C D and
that will maybe help a bit out of his
current predicament of being twenty
second now I don't see the Chinese in
sixth place but that's where her Chong
the world champion is of course don't
worry he won't worry because he got two
more rounds provided he gets through
this one semi-final and a final to come
top eighteen to qualify he's in sixth is
reversed three-and-a-half somersaults
with tuck well it's a big dive from her
Cheung Olympic champion four years ago
and of course he's not bothered really
you know he's in seventh after the
second round he knows that he will be
steadfast and consistent throughout and
so that is just an example I don't know
whether it's worth a nine but it will
get eight eight and a half so it's a big
dive and that will shoot him up the
leaderboard
9 snow not quite to 88.5 for her Chong
but for the time being he does go into
first place but the standard has been so
tough early on may not remain there for
very long if Gannicus Nets off reverse
three and a half we're tuck up to a 3.5
on the degree of difficulty oh now the
crowd reaction was the same as mine it's
not a good one that could make it more
difficult for the Russian here lands on
the end of the diving board into the
tuck shape all looks good so far
reversal in half just kicks up to AI and
now it's time to get your surfboard side
Surf's Up what a shame you can do
something goose grease now I can leave
Prasad
yeah this is yeah this is gonna make it
difficult I think he's got a good buffer
he's gonna have to dig deep 45 that's
gonna hurt isn't it big time 45 he's
gonna go shooting down the rankings he
was 8,000 I've to he might find himself
struggling for qualification after this
round if everybody dives the way they
have been Daniel
Aurora of Mexico back two and a half
with pike 19th place tipping over a
vertical there as he went in only 3.0 a
few of the divers opting to use it's
worth mentioning that the divers have to
go in different directions six dives and
five groups have died forward backwards
which is what you're looking at here
inwards which is where you stand
backwards spin forwards reverse is where
you walk down the diving board jump away
from it in spin backwards towards it and
the twist group and then you also get
another option divers here today doing
six dives five different groups
hopefully that explains some of the
intricacies well this rounds proving to
be a bit of in thought maybe
catastrophic for some of the divers a 45
followed by a 54 now sniffing effect
he's giving great encouragement after
that drops dive completely missed dive
in round two so he's not gonna qualify
but this is forward two and a half or
two twists yeah it's really good to see
he had almost a standing ovation then
you can see his teammates there knowing
that it takes a lot of courage to
it's all over for Stefan his Olympic
dreams are as good as over because this
is his only event and unfortunately with
that failed second round dive that it's
impossible for him to make it through to
the semi-final so he's diving it out now
it's a long wait I'm sure he just wants
to get it over with but he's showing you
know his courage and his professionalism
and he's carrying on six-point-five
across the board as we get confers
Bradshaw doesn't hang around for anybody
least of all me for two and a half two
twists yep
you know hang time there for Braccio
either he's a little bit low on the
water it's a big dive is three point
four this is his most complicated or one
of his most complicated dives he needs
to be on the end of the diving board
there to give himself half a chance
so it's average well obviously good so I
guess sevens maybe small yeah maybe
maybe not a little bit scruffy I don't
know let's see the judges know either
look at that six up to seven they
weren't quite sure either sixty six
point three that's to very low tariffs
no tariffs or those scoring dives
together now say czar Castro can you
change all that with a forward two and a
half somersaults to twist spike three
point four he always seems to lose his
feet as he goes into the water there's a
busy dive it didn't have a lot of time
but it's really neat and tidy
oh he's hanging ten or ten toes over the
end of the diving board manages to
complete the tie four let's have a look
here as he goes in did you see his feet
split so maybe the judges will penalize
him well maybe it happened so quickly
that they didn't see it you wait and see
did very well there with his toes all
the way over the end God say the best
judging has always been in the final
this week when we're down to the the
best judges in the fewer countries but
at 7.5 gives him a seventy six point
five zero with the multiplication on
that degree of difficulty back at the
Olympics for the second time 12 years
Ken you know nice work from Kenny very
elegant dive up and yeah he's performing
consistently well today that's him was
he in the top 10 he was yes top 10 after
the first two vines beautiful
third-round dive
halfway through his contour
and he certainly where he wants to be in
striking distance of the semi-final
spots well others are faltering but he
isn't and the good series of dives 71
followed by an 81 followed by a 72 and
after absence of 12 years his return to
the Olympics is being pretty good so far
patrick housing in 12 for two and a half
two twists yes very solid watching his
teammate having a tough day at the
office it's down to Patrick now to
represent Germany and get through and he
is a very very good diver and I would be
surprised to see him not go through and
that's three out of three for hosting so
far that could squeeze over 80 points
his three point four it's good yeah Joe
just just inputting into their machines
coming up on the scoreboard in front of
us and then in front of the viewers at
home eighty one point six zero for
housing 12 in Shanghai the world
championships last year
here comes Alexi rigged or off with his
back two and a half so I saw 3.0 his
easiest I've only 3.0 opting to play a
little bit safer than some of his other
high-risk dives and yep he's plopped it
on his head he's not going to get more
than seven and a half so eights but it's
where he needs to be squeezing into the
pike shape moving back a little bit from
the diving board causing a few
discrepancies with the control into the
hot tub and they little way for us at
home sixty 7.50 minor one little bit
more than that but it's a low degree of
difficulty so probably worth about that
Xavier Alana Garcia for three and a half
somersault spiked three point one that's
almost there for javi just a little bit
off his game again entering the water
short you'll see on the replay you're
looking for that vertical entry in
having a not quite hanging on to his
shape long enough just let's go a little
bit early a little shorter vertical him
hope for a bit more get eight and he was
he 14th after the second
and yeah so he's certainly gonna get
through to the semis if he continues to
stay in that region seventh of the
moment you know obviously you drop down
a few more notches yet but the moment
he's a little bit of daylight between
himself and the struggle is now Chris
Cole wall gives us a big smile every
time before he performs his dives here
comes his third round attempt on a four
two and a half somersaults and two
twists pike worth three point four with
the degree of difficulty it's good Chris
is back loaded his list so this is where
he starts to to bring out his big gun so
this is a first of his three point force
in succession so here we are lands on
the end beautiful heard of steps such
great rhythm and timing as very precise
it will be squeezing high 70s maybe even
80 points out of that dive it's exactly
where he needs to be yeah anything
80-plus is always good and it's right on
the cusp of an eighty seventy nine point
nine zero for Cole well lifts him up to
third now this man started like a train
this is a huge dive and this could be
the difference between him qualifying
and not forward four and a half summer
sorts for Ross eight in the tuck
position there we go
he's that could be the comeback King
he's just got his claws out and he
started to fall himself back into
contention a beautiful first round dive
an absolutely diabolical second round
dive and then he's nailed his most
difficult one three point eight the
forward four and a half somersaults in
the tuck position Wow
here we go well that's a good recovery
very very good recovery from Ross a 7.5
times that degree of difficulty gives
him mid 80 fives so a reparation job has
started one and truly for the Frenchman
to move on to the young Canadian
Francois in bought du Lac a third after
round two needs to make up some ground
back two and a half somersaults with
Pike 3.0 degree of difficulty for in
both Dulac
yep he's nice and steady today fudge-wad
he certainly will probably be one of the
the ones that doesn't quite make the cut
but if he stays there and other people
are faltering he could certainly sneak
up into top 18 I think he was in the
early 20s after has a rank after that
second round I'll probably keep him
about that place after his third vines
the mark is 63 it's seven so it was a
low degree of difficulty so our favorite
mark returns again the way it gone
missing it
63 in blue do like Ilya Zakharov first
after round 2 after round 1 reverse
three and a half sneaks it in there
I did actually move towards Bob there
not because I wanted to get closer to
pop but because I thought Zach offers a
little bit close to the diving board
there actually when he goes by his okay
let's have a look yeah he's okay he
didn't want to do a Greg Louganis
and fortunately Gregory gayness of
course World and Olympic champion his
head in dramatic fashion on a reverse
dive in the 88 games no Greg Louganis
first Acker off today well that's good
82 points be in the lead a 2.25 and Greg
is mentoring a lot of the USA divers
here now a liqu reverse two and a half
somersaults with pike for de Partie very
interesting indeed a party playing it
safe normally doing the reverse three
and a half which is what we saw from
zakharov playing safe here with the 3.0
so it needed to be very good and it was
just that beautiful you could just see
that technique this should get nines and
it needs to get nines because beautiful
slow motion look at that looking at
where he's being spotting moving his
chin looking at the water leaving his
toes towards the scoreboard and then he
goes all in less than 1.8 seconds well
he knows how to do it does Alex twice a
so a medalist at the Olympics hasn't
quite got the demeanor I'd like to see
from Alex mo he kind of has that
slightly hangdog
look hopefully that will return the
smile will return anyway in the
semi-finals reverse two and a half
somersaults one half twist four in the
okiya vouchers nailing his dives
slotting them in and that's exactly what
he needs to do dive after dive that's
three out of three for kovash up big
degrees of difficulty as well he's not
messing around for his fifth round I
missed his lowest degree of difficulty
but at the moment he's very much in the
mix how much in the mix is he well
seventy nine point two zero puts him for
the time being at least into third place
looking fairly comfortable for
qualification they were not even halfway
yet remember three more rounds still to
come
it's a young Colombian Sebastian V I
guess turn it up for two and a half
somersaults to twist three point four
just a little bit low on the water you
can certainly see the difference between
some of the stronger divers here we are
the young Colombian he does a good job
here's a double twist after the one half
some sauce he's the completion of the
time just running out of room he
probably won't get more than sixes on
that one just showing you how difficult
these dives are 68 for Sebastian via
Castaneda
on my front page just in 14th place
listen to that raw seventeen and a half
thousand people the majority of which
are favoring of the Brits Chris me is
learning the lessons previous divers
have had taking his time and just
soaking up the atmosphere before he gets
his full concentration on a reverse
two and a half somersaults one and a
half twist three point three degree of
difficulty
yeah it's currently 15th after round two
little bit short as he goes in but the
crowd liked it they're ripping the roof
off here those Christmas Mum and Dad
avid supporters of their son here we are
swinging the arms one and a half twist
into the two and a half summer sauce
just a little short of vertical that
means while you're struggle to get more
than seven switch you ever seen the
markets who await will not spoil your
surprise
mm 6.5 can I boo I'm not allowed to do
that's fairly unprofessional like a
normally am really can Quang are
Malaysia reverse two and half
somersaults one half twist you can be at
home if you of course if you want to
walk following me is with the same dive
three point three degree of difficulty
so it's big it's tricky here we are
here's the one and a half twist moving
safely away from the diving board little
bit scruffy is a better effort than
Chris me is probably gonna get seven
seven point five steady from the thirty
year old from Malaysia formerly China
there are times when Leon gets a little
bit personal story probably big and
tricky again but don't mind it does have
no time to time now to Jack law again
the crowd responds lots of Union flags
and that's the Tim meter ball we'll see
you later on in the week go down seven
meters you'll find Jackie law of
qualifications reversed over the end of
the diving boards hanging ten and that's
not good especially when you need to
stay in balance spin backwards look at
this hanging ten he did well to stay on
skips off the diving board just showing
how talented this young boy is he's only
17 he's really young in the competition
squeezing into that tuck shape as tight
as he possibly can waiting jaw oh this
is gonna be tough for Jack now it is
gonna be very tough indeed when he get
marks like that is the idea five point
five and that is going to be a big dent
in this helps a qualification not
completely irreversible but it's gonna
be tough now oh it's another tidy died
beautiful entry into the water
maybe his aerial work isn't quite as
impressive as strong as some of the
divers but you can certainly see why
he's earned his spot here in the Olymp
liveries superb entry into the water
splash this 7.5 s i think so
mice reaction really works in a very
very poor opening round dive and he has
since recovered very very well indeed
7.5 s good total seventy six point five
zero now to the first of the italians
here's to my sovereign LD are they back
two and a half somersaults with mike
25th after round two but a couple of
people have faltered just above him
there's a chance for the first of the
two Italians will see to move up a few
spaces
yes he will yes he will indeed beautiful
dive three points a vote needed to be
good it's all about being consistent
seeing some divers starting to fall
turnout
tomaso that one of his better efforts
today
will he get 70 points I don't think he'd
be too far away that heartbeat in the
backgrounds quite dramatic here in the
pool well I don't think we need any more
drama I think we've heard plenty of
drama thank you very much I think you
could cope with it Tommaso Rinaldi with
that mark for him now Ching Kai of China
seventh after round two here comes a big
one from him three point five reverse
three and a half oh so big dive indeed
three point five it's the one that we
just saw Jack Lord make a bit of a mess
of but no mistakes punching Kai here
landing on the end of the diving board
up up and away white above the five
meter and then drops into the water
making it look easy
will he get 90 points may be very close
to just shy of eight point five for King
Kai but slipped him up to second place
Acker off though holding firm in first
try ado may was in fifth place after
round two so very comfortable in terms
of looking forward to qualification for
or the semies back two and a half
somersaults with pike the man from the
USA 3.0 degree of difficulty on his
third round dive yeah this is a dive
that Troy used to start with maybe a
little bit shaky for him at the
beginning seems to have moved it to the
middle of his program it's his lowest
degree of difficulty so it needs to be
good and that's a good effort from to me
that I've not seen him diving this well
for many many years in fact he's in the
form of his life and he's 32 years old
which of course isn't very old for
everyone at home but in diving terms
it's getting on a bit now something me
feel nature makes me feel positively
ancient I've got to tell you that much
thank you very much seventy six point
five zero for Troy dumain if you don't
mind granddad will introduce the next
diver now Castillo quarter three point
eight yeah we've seen this before seen
it go right we've seen it go wrong and
forward four and a half summer sorts
with tuck for the Mexican and I think
that's somewhere in between somewhere in
between right and wrong it's good and it
certainly will keep you out in
contention it's high-risk it's good to
see him using it here in the polymer
East not hiding using all his big dives
forward for now look at the strain on
his face hanging on there four foot well
for dear life but that's worthwhile
worth look at the face where you go
careful I know forward four and a half
so impressive and it's good it'll get
more eighty points will it let's see mmm
thinking about to here restraining order
on him for some time yeah Castillo
welter comes up with eighty one point
seven zero one danger money keeps doing
that now on to Rodriguez robert pirs
Rodriguez I've been this way on a pike
position for his back two and a half Oh
all right you know it's when you're
comparing contrasting with the best in
the world you can see here he's only 18
Robert Rodriguez and you can see it's a
little bit here in there little bit
scruffy it turns in it doesn't quite
turn into it but
does an impression of a banana on the
end there loses his legs a little bit of
course the judges don't see the replay
but they did pick up on those
discrepancies forty-nine point five zero
not a great mark my great succession of
scores and he will be struggling to
return in the semi-finals - Michaela
benedetti
take it a little bit more time more
considered over this dive because the
last one he rushed into very quickly
back two and a half somersaults this
time for his third round I have 16th
after round 2 this one in the position
nice really nice third round dive there
completing this third third round from
Italy
Michaela Benedetti 3.0 so it needed to
be good and that's very good bag full of
eights and he'll certainly shift himself
up the rankings a little bit with that
one especially with quite a few divers
faltering on round three halfway yep
half way three done three more to go and
then dirty picks up 72 3/8 x the degree
of difficulty
so now we change the judges and we look
at the score and half wait Nidia
zakharov impeccable so far in first
place Chinese two and four Webster's
having a good time as I say one of the
Americans is doing worse both Americans
on that front page anyone German now in
contention now what's happening on page
two I examine the day party has moved
into a position to qualify as has nearly
the Greek their 19th place good recovery
by Papa RunAs do you don't see the
British flag on there do you because
Christmas is 21st check law its 26th
Chris not that far away
Jack quite some way away you'll have to
really pick up his game last three dives
to have any chance of qualification
sniffing tech savvy well and truly out
of it after dropping around two new
judges in place what was clap themselves
will be the judge of that thank you very
much at the end of your three rounds I
think it's important that the the judges
are changed it's a long long competition
and everyone gets tired including you
and I Bob so we need to hold our
concentration but when you're judging
dive after dive after dive after dive
after dive after dive you get a bit
tired so mix out the judges fresh panel
the dive is obviously remain the same
halfway yes there to go break Duluth wow
they get a break in between the judges
have to judge every dive the divers have
to do one dive every round that's a
great shot that's a really great shot
from the same region bawdy we're seeing
that a lot more towards the end of the
week when we have the women's ten meter
and the men's which people keep asking
me where is it it's on Friday the
preliminaries and the semi-finals on
Saturday morning
that's UK time of course wherever you're
watching in the world and the final is
at seven o'clock British Summer Time on
Saturday evening now Ethan Warren first
diver in round four in the comfort zone
at the moment in 10th in with three and
a half summer sorts with tuck three
point four kind of a middling dive with
still plenty of danger attached to it
this is definitely not a middling dive
3.4 degree of difficulty this is as
tough as it comes on the inward move
gotta stay right over the diving board
squeezing into the Tuck shape gotta stay
close enough to make it but jump far
enough away to miss it you can see him
almost landing on his chamois there
which is what the divers used to drive
themselves off obviously using that as a
little bit of a spotting technique he's
on his head again it's okay and it's a
big score because of the degree of
difficulty semi 6.50 thumbs up at the
smile from Ethan the time being he moves
into first now we've seen a bit of
accurate sake performance by Damien
Seeley so far as he was reversed three
and a half some sorts with tuck is like
it's worth three point five on the DD
he's done okay with it he did kind of
turn his body towards us as he came into
the end of the diving board I'm not
quite sure why he did that or how come
as you can see just facing slightly skew
if but not to skew if for the judges to
penalize he's moving sideways a lot
actually let's see if we get an overhead
shot you have to take it for me he was
moving sideways which will impact the
entry into the water just drifting as he
goes in we call that cast in diving and
we are cast in fishing as well don't
they
sounds like I know what I'm talking
about got a clue when I'm talking about
quite frankly being it would be the
first time her Chong of China in with
three and a half somersaults with tuck
three point four damn I like about the
Chinese I'm like some of the other diets
we've seen today they are studied and
very methodical the way they do things
they don't rush into a tie they take all
the time it's allowed to them its forth
after round three well that is still
very very good but I'm a little
surprised it was splashy on the entry as
we saw there from her tongue normally
drilling his entries with such precision
and this one he's attempting to empty
the pool maybe empty in the pools a
little bit harsh but he's throwing up
much more splash than we're used to so
he might struggle to get eights on that
he did all the hard work and then just
letting the dive go over just not happy
not happy without not happy her what do
we think
eight and 7.5 about right definitely
okay well one of the eights will count
as we move on to Afghani Kuznets off
forward two and a half seven sorts to
twist three point four he's got to get
his dig his heels in and take its toes
and actually and start getting back up
this field twenty-second not as he xx
after yeah xx after the third round dive
third round I've let him down this one
will help they will probably get sevens
but I would have imagined it way
definitely needs more than seven Stu to
make his comeback could we see an upset
happening team GP with some work to do
and Russian number two with some work to
do still xx after round three that would
not improve his situation let's
everybody else screwed up on their dive
and see what we can get from the Mexican
who's next up and you know rope verse
three and a half so I'm supposed to be
tucked
well it's the biggest die from the young
Mexican a shame really
he managed to get the aerial work all in
the right place all he needed to do was
push his feet up a little bit higher up
as he entered the water let's have a
look he just lets go a little bit early
turned into a bit of a banana back and
goes into the water 6 is a shame really
because he did all the hard work and
they just miss miss ya miscalculated his
exit from the dive and gets for his
pains it might have been quite painful
about 160 8.25 that's not gonna help him
it was 27th before damn he's gonna move
up a great deal after that well let's
see how the crowd reacts to the next man
on the board Contreras Bradshaw of
Venezuela because he's in that kind of
territory with Chris Meers and Jaco in
particular moment back two and half
summer sorts with Mike for the
Venezuelan well if you if you're
expecting Stephane fake he's obviously
pulled out of the competition because
we've just skipped a dive up confused me
for a few seconds but now he moved on to
the Venezuelan so Stephan fact who
failed the dive obviously suffered a bit
of an injury when he slipped off the
diving board in dramatic fashion and
he's at the Venezuela and they're back
two and a half in the pike position
pretty middle-of-the-road sevens but
he's still you know performing
consistently 2021
marks are as follows all the lines
through those marks do not count so the
sevens all do and we have 63 just to
confirm for you to confuse me for a bit
as well seventh is no longer in this
competition he's gone but says our
Castro very much in it with his back two
and a half somersaults 12 after round
three
yep it's okay from stays up this is
lowest degree of difficulty so it needed
to be good 3.0 it's got a couple of Lodi
DS in there as we call them and this is
one of them a couple more to follow
actually finishing his list with his all
of his dives a little bit basic which
always makes it difficult for him to get
in unless of course he's diving
consistently which he is I expect him to
continue to do that and to sneak through
into the semi-final yeah more than
sinking at the moment but as plenty of
divers still to go third place for him
good know he continues to have a good
day and this is what it's all about dive
after dive consistency you can see lots
of divers faltering and the divers who
are the ones who continue to focus on
the job continue to land upright on
their heads just like Kenny's doing
there for us high 70s for that diver
would imagine three point three degree
of difficulty good work Kenny well I
gotta say 71 followed by an 81 followed
by a 72 full of - seventy nine point two
zero
we've had some consistent performers in
the competition so fine he's certainly
up there amongst them Patrick how's ding
comfortable top 10 at the moment in with
three and a half summer sorts with tuck
three point four four the only German
now remaining in the competition
you are precise steady unfaltering and
unwavering big Thai fervor for Patrick
three point four it's quite tall for a
diver so he needs to get his technique
spot-on and he does just that moving a
safe safe distance from the diving board
maybe a little bit too far away actually
struggled a little bit with his entry
into the water if he gets a bit nearer
and a bit higher could get nines seven
and a half so for that one seventy eight
point two zero the total Marco's over
the 300 points for Patrick housing likes
a bragger off starting with the very
high diver there's a high tower of 23.5
on the reverse three and a half summer
sorts almost crashing out at the
semi-finals there he did a great job
there in the end
let's have a look at this take off yet
just skips forward then you see that
skipping off at the knees and the hips
and hangs on for dear life and just a
bikes and nice and that is sneaky that
must have hurt yeah that'll definitely
job is back but as as divers we're used
to being beaten up by the gym in the
water and occasionally that's the way
you just is body Williams going in there
you know snapping you're spying the way
you just need to be tough for a newer
diver reverse right now have some
thoughts for Garcia of Spain better
effort there from javi needed a big one
and a good one to get it in and that's
certainly what he's done with his force
fourth mind a reverse three and a half
it's a big dive squeezing in beautiful
elevation pops his feet up and slips
into the water the night much of a trace
78 points yeah I think they're happy
I work out with a Canadian coach what
was he clapping that would be Spanish I
didn't notice which I did so my impale
in the week you're lucky
Chris go well reverse one-and-a-half
seven sawed three and half twist it's
the first time we've seen this dive
three point four is a degree of
difficulty in the free position again we
have seen a free dive can you explain
that after we've seen it it's very much
a classic dive for any multiple twisting
dive less than one and a half
somersaults or one and a half
somersaults all or less it is in the
free position because you don't hold a
position a pike or tuck for longer than
half a rotation so it just squares it up
nicely in the end 3.4 degree of
difficulty you don't see I think it
might be the only competitor choosing to
use this one and a game of tactics
working for Cole will their three point
four it's a good dive yeah what the
judges think new set of judges of course
they've gone with the 881 point a second
Macy Ross a is gone here he goes he made
a real hodgepodge of his second round
dive and now he's come out all guns
blazing this is the comeback King he's
gonna absolutely sail above 85 points
buries his entry there slipping into the
water he's hardly throwing up any splash
Wow this is the way to get yourself back
in contention I'm gonna have to hold up
a card say I'm not ready ask him to do
it again do it again
that was brilliant eighty seven point
five zero it was brilliant
Andros a has really recovered so well
Francois in BO du Lac his biggest dive
so far three point five degree of
difficulty reversed three and a half
somersaults with tuck yes some work to
do to the top 18 25th at the moment he's
done well with it
notice there he's three dive routine he
tends to stop there take a big breath
close his eyes potentially visualized
the dive and then he sets off very
composed he is a little bit tight to the
diving board here I might add
he's okay he turns into a bit of a fog
kick as he comes out the breaststrokers
would have been pleased with that one
anyway that's a good diamond it's his
highest degree of difficulty hanging on
to the top of his kneecaps oh look at
those Fox legs as he comes out rabbit
that's very unkind we start talking
about your personage in the moment now
Don - Ilya Zakharov
this man has been the model of
consistency stand by the commentators
curse no he is consistent even with a
dodgy takeoff no smiles from the Russian
coaches they're here to do business way
back from the end of the diving board
and I did think that he'd struggle with
that but he is superb that can be even
better he needs a better hurdle step on
his next dive because he adds in it
another twist to that dive which goes up
23.92 grave difficult anyway were tee
that out that's 81 I believe the
succession of scores 86 84 8281
just don't get measured up for that
Alexandre de Partie inward three and a
half somersaults we're tuck the top
Canadian three point four degree of
difficulty oh it's a good dive little
short vertical but this is the dive that
Alex hit his head on this is the dive
that six weeks ago he smacks his head
into the springboards it would have been
about this point that he would have
connected with the diving board and
scalped himself 21 stitches on his
forehead and he's here today six weeks
later showing true courage in true class
and he's still in the hunt to make it
through not enjoying it today but he's
not enjoying it look his face tells you
that when he's on top of his game it's
all smiles and waves but today it's just
get the job done in here kabocha
reversed three and a half somersaults
with tuck 3.5
or the Ukrainians rocking and rolling
alongside the Russians they got some big
big dives all of them have they are
busting it out today and yep nowhere to
hide and everyone needs to keep up with
them
Wow I wonder if they can hold this
consistency throughout the prelims and
the semis and into the final of course
the scores do not carry so whatever the
divers do today it's about shuffling the
pack and earning a berth into the
semi-finals
Russia won Ukraine 3 at the moment in
terms of the pecking order with China in
second with her charm via Castaneda
of Colombia a big tariff 93.5 the back
three and a half it's a big time really
big time standing back was it's 3.5
because you don't get the hurdle step to
assist you as you do on the reverse
three in half this is a standing start
if you will Wow he does very well there
squeezes in runs that lid runs out a
room a little bit well I'm very
impressed that's good he's got some big
decrease of difficulty coming up now
what the judges have to say about that
coach I say give him a cuddle already
sixty eight point two five is his total
marks well you might have guessed the
first of the two Brits yes Chris Meers
standing on the 3-meter springboard
waiting to perform here's a forward two
and a half somersaults were to twist and
we could most consistent of the two
Britain's today 21st
as decisive dive and he's nailed it when
he can't when he needed to yep
Tom likes it and I agree with Tom Daly
so I could die for mirs fourth round
needed to be good attacks it out into
the double twist down into the pike
ripping that entry that's it back in
contention maybe even fact in that
all-important top eighteen
super-slow-motion
can't even keep up with it in slow
motion can we know it's great really
great well done Chris good stuff eight
across the board eighty one point six
zero has given himself a really good
chance now with that it's two more round
still to go let's look at the former
Chinese now Malaysian going for a
reverse three and a half somersaults
with tuck he's ten years and years and
years of training he does look a little
bit look as sharp as he used to in his
here in his younger days
here we are reversed three and a half
thirty years old squeezing into that
touch shake popping his feet up just
needed to be a little bit higher for
that a rip entry into the water
it'll get over seventy five points so
and it'll certainly keep him in the mix
for a semifinal spot easily actually 77
for
thank one now jackal or you know as you
look around and take up the plaudits of
the crowd you have some work to do here
laddie 17 years of age of star in
Harrogate European junior champion just
a few years ago for three and a half
somersault this needs to be good yes may
be feeling the pressure it needs to be
better than that come on Jack your
double world junior champion double
junior European champion you've been in
these senior competitions now you are
the youngest competitor and there's more
to come
more to come from this young man he's
not going to move up the field with this
this is going to keep him outside the
top 18 that's gonna put a lot of
pressure on his two dives to come but
I'm confident that he can respond do you
know what I think I look on the face of
Jack tell she really all you need to
know at this stage I think he thinks I
was starting to think that perhaps he's
not gonna be returning tomorrow I hope
that's not the case now he will be so
far lost Papa RunAs 19th place it's a
really really poor start he's done a
good reparation job not quite completely
o yet in with three and a half
somersaults with tuck three point four
degree of difficulty he's in 19th place
after round three
oh here you go up the degree of
difficulty increase the risk and
obviously increase the probability of
error and that's what we see here from
the young diver of Greece squeezes into
the top just stays in it too long and
lands in a forward roll position yeah
over he goes and died and the marks go
mm well shame
well shame because he was doing so well
but not gonna miss two fallacies day I'm
afraid any of those marks that's gonna
take him pretty much out of contention
for a top place where's Tomas old
Rinaldi still has a chance again this
has to be a 3.0 as well reverse two and
a half seven sort with Mike
you always done really well there
sneaking the diamond look - so who's
gonna go over a vertical on the entry
the hips and bones that needs to get it
in all good so far great aerial work
beautiful Pike and Lincoln exit just
tips over but tries to sneak it in and
if the judges will let him get away with
that they might only give him sevens or
he might sneak some eights interesting
bodoni judging me seriously I just want
because you would be a hanger man flog
of joy to Anu be sticking in there guys
I spotted that I know your little tricks
the keyword Jun CAI for China in word
three and our seller sorts with tuck
today things going yep it's good and you
know well he likes it Chinese contingent
there many of them a big entourage to
support this team and they of course in
this contest in twenty five time will be
looking for six out of six at the moment
King Kai battling out with the
restaurant for those semi-final spots
and that's certainly going to help his
cause he'll sail over eighty points
without three point four I've seen it
better but it doesn't need to be any
better than that to make it through
today yeah number one but one in three
the Chinese now the order has changed
Acker off off the top spot for the first
time and China 103 Russia in number two
with zakharov now Troy do mate who is in
a very good position to be returning for
the top a team find nothing goes wrong
on the final two dives three dives he'll
be fine in with three and on our summer
sorts would tuck three point four yeah
it's good form to mate he is a little
low on the water some of the other
divers completing the dive with much
more time to spare to mate a little bit
low here we go squeeze one two three can
see way below the board as he finishes
but he's so neat and tidy and he sneaks
it in there well there you go 75 points
plus I think so we may as you know so
don't you inbuilt totalize a tour in
your and your brain doesn't and built
totally zeta seventy eight point two
zero I'm not quite sure where that came
from
yeah El Castillo cuenta Mexico yes
having a really good competition
third place after the last round reverse
three and a half some shots with tuck
3.50 yes it's good yes maybe going loose
in his lower back as he kicked out of
the dive there so he will not be getting
nines the aerial works good look at that
way above the five meter squeeze that
look just lower back arch there he does
sneak it in yep little safe passage
another two dives for yoga studio well
he's done all the hard work early on so
we've got a bit of not being quite on
top of his game now but that should be
fine it should be okay robert pirs
overawed Regas reverse three and have
some sorts for the venezuelan oh well
done Rodriguez moving around a little
bit there as he was coming into the end
I wasn't quite sure where he was going
to land on the end of the diving board
but he ended up all right maybe corner
board on the far side and he plays the
waiting game and just launched that one
on his head that'll be his biggest score
each dive look right on the corner whoa
we've seen what happens from there
sometimes but that's a good dive why
don't we guess see what the marks are
big smiles from the judges still waiting
for them to come up on our screen
and yeah that's a biggest score by a
long way 63 is previous best 18.5 so
been deci won't wait for me either well
no he won't
and neither should ii cuz he just wanted
to get that one in he's finishing up the
competition he's the guy us to wait the
longest and he just wants to get his
dives done every work is good on this
he's a little bit scruffy as he exits to
dive look at this losing his feet a
little bit but he does get it together
on the end it's okay if it gets over 70
points you'll stay there well there
abouts so some divers with some work to
do Michaela I think he'll be there is he
yeah 17th all right let's find out after
we see the Bend Ettie score yeah our
daily office isn't it really tough work
who's there who's anywhere and who's
nowhere at this stage after round four
Ching Kai moves into first place
Chong in third place Ilya Zakharov still
looking very consistent near the top
come ashore to of Ukraine that's the top
ten and they parties moving into the top
ten where he deserves to be now who else
is there and who is not Chris Meers is
now we don't at the moment see jack law
on that page Kuznetsov's moved outside
the top 18 after such a good start as
well just amazing how the second half
can undo all the good work Francois in
will do left has got some work to do as
have everybody on that scream
of course we've lost Stefan feck after
the last round he's not performing
anymore
you know idea of this rather beautiful
Aquatic Center they cost a lot of money
but it's very very different giving it
huge plaudits but the diving board is
exactly the same as it is anywhere else
three meters he comes
Ethan Warren's reverse three and a half
it's a good tie for Warren fit rind and
he's for dive so far being good diving
better in training didn't quite land
with his feet together on the end there
one foot in front of the other little
bit peculiar Blee he squares it up
alright in the end and yeah he just
needs to continue to get his last dive
in on his head and he will make it
through
steady diving for Warren more to come my
feet I think from this Australian yeah
just warming up and again a big smile
from the Australian so you know as a job
is virtually done if not quite done yet
Demi and Sealy of France 19th after
round four when I was just flirting with
danger I'm not returning for the top a
team back three and a half somersaults
with tuck and we're up there in the high
tariffs three point five on this one oh
it's a little bit scruffy and this could
be good for the home advantage of the
British boys both of which are fighting
with this young Frenchman to get into
the top 18 it's a big dive it's one of
his biggest 3.5 just a little turn as he
goes into the water I don't know whether
the judges will go to town on him and
buy go to town home I mean take marks
off if you get seven to seven point five
so you'll get over seventy which is very
good for this dive I don't know which
way it's gonna go for some of these
divers as expected tight judges think
seven seventy three point five zero
after you multiply that with the degree
of difficulty that's how you get that
total and just to recall and recap
you don't get those marks with the lines
through them included in the score from
bottom scores multiplied by the degree
of difficulty now perch on the big one
the 3.8 forward four and a half yeah
that's how you do it he makes it look so
easy and let me just be clear for you
all at home that is one of the most
difficult dives possible from the
3-meter springboard look how he almost
goes up to 7.5 meters how is that
possible well it is because her tongue
has always been that strong we liken him
to Sir Chris Hoy with the size of his
thighs in relation to the rest of his
body and that could get 90 points let's
see ninety one point two zero eight
still not happy with it but never happy
we haven't seen any tens yet any of the
competitions this week I'm sure we'll
see them I guess the same isn't final
surely now because Nets off last dive
might have done for his chances bass got
some chance to repair the damage here
back two and a half somersaults one the
hard twists that will help that will
help he's one of the well my
frontrunners I expected him to see him
well in the business end of the field
and instead he's flapping around outside
the semi-final places so the tape
holding him together one and a half
twist two and a half somersaults goes in
few people asking about the judges
you're going to D seven marks come up on
your screen the two highest and two
lowest are taken away those are the
marks with the lines through them those
three marks that count are added
together multiplied by the degree of
difficulty to give the total on this
case of seventy four point two five yes
questions about the tape as well a lot
of people ask you about why so many of
the divers going to be taped up today
and what the purpose of that is and what
kind of advantage that is but they all
address that little later on we've seen
Daniel a role for the inward three and a
half somersaults three-point-four
performed in the Tuck position this time
oh very nice indeed the young Mexican
diver coming into Wow I kind of formed
the Mexicans have been showing I mean
he's way off the pace at the moment but
that's a really good dive so let's see
him with three and a half in the Tuck
position very good time
so the taping as I understand is to add
you know stimulation to the area so if
you've got a weakness on the lower back
or a certain area is to add support to
keep the blood flow in the area and or
to stimulate it in such a way so the
diver is very aware of it so to add
support so much strain going through the
body that some of the divers need
holding together the anchors obviously
needs they're quite obvious you've got
to support the particular joints but
along the back just adding in trouble
well he he made it he made it now I
think this might be one of the dive
that's played again in the bloopers tape
because he swings his arms completely
the wrong way and I've not seen a diver
manage to do that before because his
technique went to absolute part he was
completely out of balance let's look at
this jumps here we go Oh arms go forward
double arm swing and then manages to
steady himself she asked about gets in
the tuck and he makes it we saw Steven
feck absolutely bomb out this young man
is managed to save it looks like it is
open
Wow I'm super impressed well done that
man wow that's a big dive and he manages
to make it with a very peculiar
unorthodox technique really isn't the
time to do sort must have vinegar pepper
is it a diving board
now on Tuesdays our cast rope our Brazil
here were two and a half several sorts
with pike yeah say so I'll finish it
strongly only 3.0 is freeze last Ivan
for the next two including this one or
this one in the next one obviously 3.0
in word two and a half in the pike
position straight up and down his
certainly make it through to the
semi-finals easy dives to finish and
he's up there over 70 points again yep
he said well he's a model of consistency
hasn't really dropped below 70 anyone's
otherwise everything has been above 70
in his program so far that's why he'll
be returning for the semi finals as we
see in the yoke Malaysian similarly with
quite the high marks he has been very
consistent all the way through looking
to return for a top 18 place oh yes
certainly will be and obviously still
one more dive to go for Kenny and that
went in with three now that's his
biggest one three point four and he's
nailed it
squeezing into that tight shape wow the
consistency and the quality of diving as
I expected is through the roof
making it very tough to make it through
there's a few of the key players who
were struggling
Kenny Yeo is not one of them well he's
not straight he's a key player and he's
not struggling he's in the mix and he
gets 70 6.50 and again he's not been
lower than seventy one point three and
any of his dives today Patrick housing
for Germany 18 Beijing reversed three
and a half three point five this is
worth
oh what a dive yep Patrick as expected
world-class in everything he does so
competes on the platform as well as a
springboard so not many divers do that
anymore not in this era people tend to
specialize but Patrick very versatile
exceptionally talented diver and proving
so today here on the springboard
let's see what the judges think about
that I think it's gonna be waiting for
confirmation of guess but it gives me a
confirmation I was looking for eighty
nine point two five that's by fives best
dive in terms of marks and likes a
bragger offs forward two and a half two
twins yeah it's good pick you off is
diving consistently look for a moment
there they needed a little bit more
height and rotation on that dive but he
manages to squeeze it in here we are one
and a half summer sauce up double twist
and down into the water it's good sevens
seven point five maybe things a little
bit lower the water for more than that
and the marks are seventy four point
eight zero for procore off thank you
Andy Walker by the way for the bit of
information I required the reason that
Xavier Garcia was getting great applause
and so much commendation from the
Canadians he is training in Canada these
days that will be why even they
represent Spain thank you for that in
with three and a half somersaults with
tuck three point four is the degree of
difficulty
nice let's go javi that's really good
working hard and it's paying off he's in
good shape so good performances all year
squeezing in tuck shape bending at the
hips bending at the knees in these kind
of spins it's really important that the
divers dry their hands you see the small
towels that you see them throwing about
the place that's for drying their hands
and their bodies to keep the warm in
between dives but also to keep their
grip on the legs when they're spinning
around because you do not want to slip
out that's a good dive eighty-one yep
and I'll see the training regime he
seemed to have him kind of looks working
tears benefit because he's in a
comfortable position right now
after that dive now Chris Cole well in
with three and a half somersaults with
tuck three point four smile disappearing
just for a moment for the Americans face
but he's really been enjoying his
campaign so far
yep smiling at the back of the board in
concentration as soon as you set foot to
walk to the end of the diving board
concentration face game face Carl will
probably one of his more difficult with
in fact his more difficult dive but he's
just struggle with this one a little bit
because he's so tall he does a good job
that he'll only squeeze sevens I think
he want more than that as he progresses
but he'll certainly be featuring in the
semi-final
yeah just case of booking your place
from the top 18 none of these marks get
carried forward to the semi-finals and
indeed the same applies to the
semi-final to the final there just a
case of hooking your place to return
tomorrow so if you're hearing noises off
from the ecology box distracting for us
I'm sure for the divers as well
ITA Ross eight back two and a half
summer sorts with Mike yeah Ross a is
such a performer I'm sure if you can
cast your mind back to earlier in this
contest where it was nearly all over for
this young Frenchman he has come back
and for dive after dive yeah he's a
strong diver this is only 3.0 to grave
difficulty but he does it very well
indeed and he'll certainly be going
through to the semi-finals and he's one
to watch
69 for Ross a 8.02 7.5 look overly tough
with it but it's good enough and he'll
be back for more in the semi-finals this
man that moment though will not France
why in BO du Lac of Canada for two and
half somersaults two twists Pike
position three point four degree of
difficulty 21st after round oh that's
one of his Bennett dives and I should
think so too because he actually ups the
ante on his final round dive this is the
forward two and a half somersaults with
two twists let's look at the replay into
the end of the time for one and a half
somersaults to twist really quickly
easily done into the water he saw before
he goes there closing his eyes
visualizing his dive leaving his
visualization quite late lots of divers
use visualization but I've never seen
someone do it right on the diving board
just before they go anyway that's one of
his best performances so far because I
should say round after round four he was
in 21st place is now in 10th place
zakharov prepares for his for
two-and-a-half summer sorts with three
twists
oh it's a big dive it is the world's
most difficult dive on the springboard
3.92 grave difficulty you're only good
to see a a couple of the guys doing this
with one two three twists oh I don't
know how you get out of that alive but
he does little bit short of vertical bit
because of the degree of difficulty that
could get him 80 points seven six and a
half seven but it's a big big degree of
difficulty high risk and he him/her
Chong and one of two others are going to
attempt that dive and he really rushed
into there as well though there was no
preparation diverse as soon as he got
the the go from the ref he was he was
off there and surprise me with it with a
degree of difficulty that that has
attached to it 3.9 that he wouldn't have
actually spent a bit more time over it
but she dives it his way now Alex de
Partie for three and a half somersaults
Pike 3.1 Alex up into 10th he prepares
to dive number 5
yeah it's good font a party does he have
enough degree of difficulty to challenge
again for his third Olympic medal only
time will tell
this is simple lots of the divers still
using this so for three and a half in
the pike position that's tipping over a
vertical as he goes in there it'll still
get eight eight and a half's I think so
technically proficient really really
good yeah it was a kid you saw in 1998
the Commonwealth Games in Malaysia being
carried head high by Tony Ali remember
that yeah well I came third in that
competition and he was the winner so yes
I do remember how pretty toy sorry to
bring that early on that's dinner offer
tonight them seventy seven point five
zero four day party Ilya Kumasi back two
and a half somersaults to Round four he
was in fourth place 3.0 attached to it
oh it needed to be a little bit better
than that you can see the taping on the
back there was another diver just jumps
into well that's Jack actually preparing
himself for his next dive here we are on
the replay no need to squeeze into the
pike a little bit deeper there just let
him go a little early arching through
the lower back obviously quite a
sensitive area taping on the feet as
well it's like action men being held
together by duct tape anyway he's still
in and still with a fighting chance yeah
I think it'd be okay wasn't a great mark
but it's pretty much done all the hard
work up to this stage and providing he
doesn't do a Stefan effect he's okay
sebastien Castaneda
is upping his degree of difficulty a 3.5
reverse three and a half with 22nd oh
what a dive very good from the young
Colombian only 20 years old this is his
big dive this is the one where all the
risk is going to be and actually that's
his best diver of the contest squeezing
into that touch shape rotating very
quickly pops it on his head that will
probably be his high scoring dive so far
and it is seventy five point two five
[Applause]
you heard the noise before you see the
diver diver bring the team gb trunks yes
Chris Meers it was enjoying this and
enjoy even more if he gets through in
the top 18 at the moment he is in 16th
place Christmas in word three and a half
somersaults with tuck around right
steady it's a little bit short as he
goes in everyone's on their feet though
the Team GB scarf the Union flag being
waved massive support here for Chris
Meers inward three and a half squeezes
in seven 7.5 s it could have been eight
and eight point five C Peter just waited
a little bit longer
dives in Southampton with Lindsey phrase
the same coaches Peter Waterfield so
could dive from Christmas he'll stay in
the all-important top 18 yes yeah 13th
of the moment but there's quite a few
divers still to go good lock him down a
peg or two to the Malaysian as we
mentioned used to die for China going
towards the end of his career has
switched to relays as part of the
synchro team the other day in with three
and a half I said pick one when he
needed it
big dive 3.4 and that's his best I've so
far showing his experience performing
under pressure the weight of expectation
that'll get close to 80 points high 70s
at least it's a good dive stepping up
when he needs to why the old memory bank
works doesn't it who did that
all that I was diving for China and now
he's doing it for Malaysia as well
Michael Oher time is running out for
qualification for him just two more
rounds 3.5 degree of difficulty back
three and a half somersaults with tuck
jack not quite cast adrift yet 25th
place study concentration on this and
not what dive for Jack law oh he's
having such a tough day it's one of his
better ties but really this young man
young boy 17 years old is so much better
than this this is straighting watching I
can only imagine what his coach Haidee
is feeling oh it's a big dive it's on
his head it's gonna sneak sevens it's
gonna get close to 70 points maybe just
over 70 points but it's not good enough
to move him up the field enough to get
in the top 80 what a tough day for Jack
oh come on he's only got one more dive
to come on time and dives marks running
out rapidly for him Savannah's Poppa
RunAs grease qualification went wrong in
the previous route here is with his
reverse three and a half several sorts
with tuck get your surfboard tape the
surf is up yeah the coach said no and
that's what happens these are difficult
dives
such a shame here we go on the end of
the diving board squeezing into the Tuck
shape as he spins backwards towards a
diving board just lets go where
too late here comes the splash maybe
back towards the diving board there we
go whoops-a-daisy not going to be his
date no representation for Greece in the
Sony files it would seem now the Italian
here also has some work to do in that
part of the field out where to pick up
big marks reverse two-and-a-half
somersaults one and a half twist for an
Aldi Bernal DS okay really afford to be
giving away any points and he's a little
short as he goes in the water there this
is one of his bigger ties three point
three there's a one and a half twist
into the two and a half somersaults yeah
needed to be a little bit better than
seventh I think and that's what you'll
get for that short just a little bit you
say real Cheltenham then R you said sure
that's a mouse-over and LD with yeah I
kind of look that says might not be
tomorrow for me there we go a big dive
this is huge three point eight two
forward four and a half quite the three
point nine we saw previously but three
point eight four with four and a half
watching kya current leader just goes to
show that even the Chinese can go
disastrously wrong you do not see that
very often making a real mess up of his
hurdle step she asked about stays on the
end of the diving board one foot
slipping off this is three point eight
you can't do this off a poor start oh
there we go
Wow did he complete the dive he did
complete the dive it's fine it's only
gonna get sore I don't know I give that
a - two and a half maybe interesting to
see what the judges do that because they
would not be expecting that one and a
half to four come on Joe it's ridiculous
that is a ridiculous spread I'm sorry
are you watching that is a ridiculous
spread that doesn't make any sense you
know the judges were confused but anyway
let's see I'm confused by the judges
Troy do make reverse three and a half
summer sorts we're tuck anything could
happen of this competitions too may
bring it back on track nailing his
reverse three and a half yeah it's all
about consistency and that is what Troy
to me has been displaying every time he
set foot on the diving board so far
these Olympic Games that's another good
dive they'll get way over 80 points and
so it should well here we go what's
gonna happen in the final round just a
few more divers of this round and then
the drama of the final round
well he's said all right he's been quite
consistent all the way through us his
biggest mark of the day eighty five
point seven five four troy do make such
a poetic doesn't realize that yeah he
Castillo well top of Mexico hope is back
somewhere I can get chance to say it
again backward two-and-a-half summer
sorts with bike I need three point zero
on this one yeah this is one of his
weaker dives all divers have to do a
dive in a different direction so all
five groups must be covered this is the
backwards group backward two and a half
somersaults the owl opting for only 3.0
lots of the divers opting for this one
and I've seen it better than that but
I've also seen it a lot worse so I don't
think that's gonna break 70 points which
is where he really needs to be if he
wants to stay with the big boys at sixty
seven point five zero for wetter I'll
show you what you're talking about half
the time well Robert spires of Rodriguez
going for a reverse two and a half some
thoughts one artists from Venezuela 28th
after Round four and that's not going to
see him move up from that kind of
placing in the standings he's only 18
years old the second youngest only
person young and enemies Jack Jack lore
from Team GB who's having a tough day at
the office
this guy's a bit well all over the place
in the nicest possible way but he's
young and he's got plenty of learning
plenty of training to go before he gets
that consistency 57 point 75 and he's
got one more dive to come and that will
be it and it will be goodbye for him
Michaela been detie give me a bit more
time to introduce him this time reverse
two and a half somersaults with one
after us Mike position three point three
degree of difficulty as a crucial dive
for Michaela and he's made it kind
always difficult right at the end of the
field you have to wait and wait and wait
and wait and watch all the other divers
Lodge their scores and then you need to
come out and responded Mickey has done
just that he's landed on his head he'll
get 7008 and so he should
it's a good dive like electrode pads on
his lower back suffering a little bit
with lower back pain so plug him into
the electricity and and help him out I
think he's a bit of a battery charge but
that might be okay 18th place so he's in
the very last qualification place after
that dive end of round five and here is
how it looks
Chong did you see what they were the
other Chinese is now after that last
dive russia USA germany mexico ukraine
USA again malaysia Canada Spain now
where's the second Chinese there they go
in Levin and Chris Mears is in as you
see on your screen no place and them
over Jack lon McKenney Ben Betty is
getting the last arm the position to the
moment but that's quite tight because
that stuff won't be back when we think
stand or caster dado Renaldi or indeed
jack law of Great Britain and step in
fact in case you're wondering why he
didn't see him he pulled out the
competition after round two
that's after round three I think it was
lots of the crowds still here and Jack
lore has got a lot to do on his last
dive I think he might have left himself
too much to do
he needs to dive of his life to
entertain this home crowd Christmas
still in the mix this is the first I've
final round of the men's 3-meter
springboard preliminary it's Ethan
Warren on Australia for two and a half
somersaults to twist pike 3.4 degree of
difficulty yet he's been steady this
evening the challenges these divers all
now need to well go back to the Olympic
Village have a bite to eat go to bed
try and get to sleep because they've got
to do it all again the next morning well
18 of them have and I'm pretty sure that
this young man Ethan Warren of Australia
will be one of those we'll see he has
this round progresses when the big Q
comes alongside their name who's
qualified will tell you that as it
appears on our screen
Ethan Warren is pretty much in there
without too much difficulty for 41.50
should get it done for him Tammy and C D
of France though in 20th place needs to
improve with the reverse two-and-a-half
summer sorts from one and a half twists
well like he was driving a bus a little
bit then so arms going everywhere
swinging around a little bit in his Pike
shape it wasn't the elegant twist and
into the pike that were used to seeing
here we go look one and a half twist
just walk shoulders shoulders shoulders
and he goes and that may help jack law
because he is level pegging with him
currently a little weak dive to finish
there a weaker dive to finish there from
this Frenchman Wow drama his case no
more room on top
60 1.05 that could be a wave goodbye
because he looks like he's not going to
be returning for the top 18 her chunk
thought about is actually it really
flunking in that fifth round I've got a
concern himself well that's an
individual competition and he's doing
pretty fine thank you in first place
after around five yeses for
two-and-a-half somersaults with three
twists in the pike position oh it's yeah
it's good I'm so impressed with this
dive he does always just split his legs
just before he goes here women show
their sixth time in Olympic medal it's
just a little bit confused as to why her
teammate did that he's the triple twist
just to might get it done and then
splits his legs they guys a bit here and
there on the finish it might get over 80
points I think you'll need to be better
than that that's a little bit of a safe
so he kind of gets in and then rolls in
the water there to give the impression
of being up by but he asked you if as he
goes in yeah he doesn't like it like
that does he temper temper eighty three
point eight five for her Chong so always
perfection with a Chinese anything less
is not acceptable okay because that's
off 21st
oh and he's gone for it he has been a
bit here and there during this
preliminary and that's his biggest dive
three point eight and he's done a very
good job on it now will it be enough
he's got that blue tape holding him
together
now has he held it together enough to
get through that's gonna be a big big
score to finish let's see how that
affects his total marks now we get to
see the mark just before he comes up on
your screen that's why I went oh sorry
kind of preempted the ninety one point
two zero you see on the screen I think
four fourteen forty that is good so that
may will be enough Daniel Arroyo of
Mexico however need something similar
and he's got a forward four and a half
somersaults
point-eight tuck 24th after around 5:00
this has to be pretty much spot-on oh
it's a good day I've just letting the
dive go over as he goes into the water
but that's not a surprise because it's
so difficult to do good hurdle step
landing right on the end up up and away
way above the five meter beautiful TUC
shape and that's one of his best dives
just letting the dive get over a
vertical which means you'll get less
than sevens probably judges say the
spread they're five up to seven when
judge didn't like it the rest of the
judges were in were consistent where's
Brad job or Venezuela 27th and again I'm
likely to return this is spectacular
three point three your verse two and a
half somersaults one and a half -
where's he's gone again now what happens
now okay so that is a technical restart
you can see the crowd getting behind the
athletes and what will happen the diver
will perform the dive as stated he will
be marked out of ten by each of the
judges and then there will be a
two-point deduction from each of the
judges before it's multiplied by the
degree of difficulty so you will not see
that on screen you would just see it in
the total score the reason he stopped is
because he was all over the shop again
on his hurdle step we have seen some
drama haven't we hear from this guy in
particular the last dive he made it
without this arm swing hurdle step again
oh that is a real calamity an absolute
shambles actually let's call it what it
is he's going to get two points
deduction from the war scores which are
going to be really really low what an
absolute shame we've seen it all today
we've seen Steven feck have to pull out
of the competition because he slipped
off the diving board and failed his dive
we've seen this guy stop get the restart
and then Wow because he got the tension
on the board wrong this is me way too
much movement on that no no no he's just
an awful take off nope he said yeah look
at that a total of four point nine five
I've not seen a dive score that low he's
too
draw ever that's actually ok of course
oh you got a feel for him absolutely
distraught hmm the ups and downs
literally of diving
I think you'll be consolable for quite
some time competition moves on however
we assess our caste rope our Brazil
reverse two-and-a-half summer sorts with
pike oh it's a very good dive to finish
from stays I needed to be he's only just
in the semi-final spot if you like so he
was 15 after the five rounds
this is 3.0 he is doing his dives very
well indeed it he needs to low degree of
difficulty in comparison to some of the
other divers very elegant quite a tall
diver very experienced 29 years old one
of the oldest competitors uses
experience and making it through safety
441 there's a lot of iron that school
there are yeah we got 440 ones for 40s
500 as well which is perch on now on to
the Malaysian Kimi yep
yes sir approaching the 400 mark himself
here's the back two and a half summer
sorts with pike for him no worries for
Kenny he's rocking and rolling he's
straight through to the semi-finals
eight after the fifth round and yeah
good performance from this young man
today I say young man young man of 29
years old one of the oldest competitors
that he was on the money today
consistent that's what you need to be he
has been a model of consistency 71 81 70
to 79 76 and another 72 to round it off
we welcoming Ken back to the semi-finals
as I think we will be providing goes
untoward here Patrick how's things
reverse two and a half somersaults twist
Wow water dive should have made a bit
more of a fuss of this one three point
seven degree of difficulty he's actually
adding a twist to what a lot of the
other divers here two and a half twist
two and a half somersaults three point
seven it's a huge dive and that'll
easily get over 80 points because of the
degree of difficulty and that's housing
through Stephen feck
out yeah waiting for the cues to come
beside the names I haven't actually
happened as yet but well because we've
got so many competitors 29 of them but I
think you can safely assume that Patrick
Houston will return I'll go out on a
limb and actually rig or off 13th place
margin for error on this one boy looked
like he was gonna do a bit of a marginal
error but he managed to hang on played
the waiting game he could sense that his
rotation was a little bit slow here we
go up here's the one and a half twist
and then he squeezed didn't think so
hang on a minute I'm spinning slow I
better bury my face in my shins and hang
on for the ride which is what he does
just about gets in there up he diverts
anything 69 point three zero what you go
through on the poor side watching your
teammates or your sons or daughters yes
you can't influence what's going on up
there just Garcia's last dive nice dive
to finish from have a reverse one and a
half somersaults three and a half twist
this is a classic dive this is what we
used to see ten years ago longer before
the multiple somersault multiple twists
came in but this is a beautiful dive it
is three point four now degree of
difficulty and have he making it count
there nice dive to finish would've been
that long ago 20 years ago all the
divers would have used this dive last
two dives both the same mark 81 0.26 0
no product placement here thank you for
60 point 3 5 from him Crisco will hate
the room knife here in February when he
took power this competition 1 Grand Prix
win this year in Fort Lauderdale on his
way to the semis
if the reverse three and a half works to
his advantage 3.5 degree of difficulty
oh yeah what a die foam core will to
finish it's a big one reverse three and
a half lot can go wrong and we've seen
that already for many of the other
competitors but core will making no
mistakes there on his final dive
beautiful dive
will it get 80 points and
you'll be too far away yes it does
eighty point five zero eight ten seven
point five remind you if you are late
coming to this all the marks with lines
through them do not count bottom marks
top marks disappear
it's the ones in the middle row say his
final forward two and a half seven sort
to twist well well say they come back
King just missing his hands he goes in
there throwing up too much splash but he
fought his way back into the top
eighteen after a complete calamity on
his second round I've I think it was
it's unusual to get the charges missing
his hands as he went in throwing up a
bit of splash on his forward two and a
half there to twist this guy has got
lots to offer and I'm glad to see him
going through to the semi-final cuz if
he's on he's gonna be up there look at
that just saying to his coach he clapped
his hands he went in that's why there
was lots of splash 4:45 not the most
animated of divers doesn't need to meet
and save all that kind of stuff for
tomorrow once he knows he's through and
he pretty much is now Francois him boo
du Lac o Canada 19th after dive number
five made up a couple of places so knows
he's almost there but this is huge
3.9 degree of difficulty for two and a
half somersaults three twists hold on
this could be a bumpy ride
oh I do not believe it that is
absolutely monumental what a dive wow I
did not see that coming look at the
smile and so it should be this is three
point nine Wow
one and a half somersaults here come the
triple twist he's at least saved his
best til last and that's gonna get
massive score wow I was not expecting
that I was expecting to how I could hear
the helicopters overhead and I was
thinking of a helicopter joke to poop
but no need for a helicopter joke
what a die man you just heard Leon
tailors voice break on air fantastic
ninety three point six zero yeah the
danger man he split the Chinese in
Shanghai last year gold to China silver
to this man and then bronze to China
will he feature again and certainly
doing a formidable job here this evening
gonna do the same again tomorrow twice
but if that's anything to go by he's on
Form will he be on fire attempted to
save that so far we just passed forward
to round six please cuz we're getting
some sensational dives in this round are
we Zakhar off ninety one point two zero
in Boonton lakh ninety three point six
zero Alex day party for two and a half
somersaults to twist three point four to
finish yes Alex's best are just moving
over vertical as he goes into the water
yeah certainly not happy Alex today but
it's the prelims you know he's a
perfectionist that's why he's double
Olympic silver medalist in this event he
knows he needs to dive better that'll
get him enough to get through and if he
ups his game tomorrow morning and ups it
again for the final he could feature but
has he got enough degree of difficulty
we will wait and see didn't have the
grace of starts but he's finishing with
a great deal of pluck and vigour and
courage as he always does and he'll be
back for more in the series as will Ilya
Kovac of Ukraine for two and a half
somersaults to
with spiked 3.4 his final dive yep while
he was all over that it was really
really good dive yeah attack in the end
of the diving board really really strong
out doubleTwist completing the dive
super smooth entry into the water with a
rip 80 points plus and a secure place in
the semi-final early tomorrow morning
it's pretty harsh isn't it tomorrow
morning let's confirm who's there Zakhar
off her Chong house ding kabocha Colwell
garcia de Partie all with queues beside
their names there will be many more
shortly but they are all definitely
through mathematically they cannot be
overtaken so all those seven have made
it through now cast Anita 22nd in with
three and a half somersaults with tuck
three point four degree of difficulty
Mike just agreed himself a little bit
too much to do
yeah just rolling over the diaper this
is what happens these competitions are
so long people start to to lose it a
little bit maybe it's concentration
maybe it's fatigue some divers raising
their game others faltering this young
man only 20 years old he'll be back
again and you could sit here the crowd
behind me as I'm speaking because who's
up next
can you guess destiny no fishes in 300
checking those marks again was to get
off the screen forget chance given to
you 400 sorry 413 at point six zero now
Chris Meers this is the big one a very
big one this will be the difference
between you making that semi final and
not I can hardly watch forward four and
a half somersaults we talk big degree of
difficulty 3.8 Christmas oh yes I think
it's going to be good enough
the Crider behind him Tom and Stacey
Sarah fellow teammates on their feet
that's a good dive it's his biggest
degree of difficulty 3.8 we've seen lot
for the other divers naylet we've seen
some of the divers falter Chris does tip
over vertical so in the splash up a
little bit away from you he does a good
job
hopefully that is enough it's not going
to get more than seven unfortunately but
I'm hoping that it doesn't get sevens
6.5 for Chris Meers doesn't get seventh
mmm got mark down there maybe just a tad
maybe worse being a bit term jingoistic
good word nice finishing strongly was in
17th yes 17th after the fifth round
functions experience is a big dive three
point four oh wow
this is going to be tight for those
remaining spots and this guy is
certainly in the hunt for one of those
well let's see is mark so now tell me
who else has definitely made the
semi-finals after this seventy-three
point one zero in boudu lakh and Ross a
latest names with a queue beside their
names I mean say top 10 are confirmed
eight places still to go for definite or
slightly forlorn look on his face
because something three point four
really has to be at the top of his game
here for two and a half somersaults to
twist
oh dear
he's just had well what happened there
landed on the end of the diving board
completely almost slipped off mistimed
there we go just buckles knees buckle
web for the big one there's no rotation
nothing he can do he just wants to swim
away wants to to disappear I really
really feel from he's only 17 he's got
so much potential that happens in
training you could Annie buckle
completely and I I really feel fun
there's nothing he could do
he's had a really bad day he's had an
awful day of diving he failed his failed
his last dive my goodness can't wait to
go chasing after him I think he'll be
long gone because he just want to get
out of here you have to understand why
that would be mr. fallows pepper unas in
with two and a half somersaults with
Pike for the Greek it's a wonderful dive
for the Greek to finish on one of his
easier dives again the 3.0 and he's
executed it just with precision this is
what we're looking for
rip entries into the water his aerial
work is good you can't see any light or
daylight in between the chest and the
thighs and he rips the entries going to
get eights
it's good but not good for Jack wow I'm
still reeling after watching that Castro
and Warren are the latest ones have cues
beside their name so they are through as
well so we now know 12 of the 18 for
definite so the few more competitors to
go yet boat before we can confirm the 18
but up to Warren they are all definitely
back few people waiting to see what
happens when the remaining dives
including Chris Meers Tommaso Rinaldi of
Italy in with three and a half
somersaults with top 20 third place
after dive number five here's his final
attempt
I think that's more he's left himself a
bit much to do that needed to be more
more points and it's gonna get just
running out of room in with three and a
half is his biggest dive you can just
see here finishing low on the water not
quite straightening out enough what will
he get I don't know five and a half six
and a half seven maybe I don't know it's
yeah I'm gonna say with this election of
judges anything's possible let's see
what they think five point five up to
seven point five looking at two point
differential there but anything ones
without what I said over them count cuz
that's not by the way he's got another
one of the berths
for the semi-finals chink I unbelievably
after round fun after almost failed dive
that wasn't his best either but it's
good enough eleventh he'll make it
through to the top eighteen some of his
teammates they're a bit confused as to
what's going on as we were in the
commentary box taping on the toes the
explanation for that is that toes get
worn out the diving board has actually
got a lot of grip on it's a bit like
sandpaper not quite as harsh as
sandpaper but when you're doing dive
after dive after dive after dive it does
rub away at you toes so a lot of the
divers using tape on their toes just to
replace the skin I guess seventy four
point two five not a happy bunny at all
but he's gonna be back for more
an improvement definitely required from
Ching Kai for a medal and the final
takes place on Tuesday night Troy Dumais
forward to and a half somersaults two
twists Pike position three point four
he's done pretty much all the hard works
just to the ended on his qualification
well he certainly does it in fine style
puts the tin lid on his qualification I
like that saying I put that into my
repertoire
here we go Fordham a very consistent
he'll be right up there in the top three
with that fantastic diving from the
already cried Olympic medalist earlier
in the week and he certainly deserves
his spot through in the semi finals
tomorrow morning yeah the chink I try do
mate is also qualified so we know 15 of
them now only three more to be or this
is agony for Chris Meers agony because
he knows he's not definitely guaranteed
a place yet it was semi-finals yeah
Castillo Webster two and a half twist
Pike three point three to finish yep
he's in no worries for y'all
I've seen him dive better two years ago
I thought he was gonna be the next big
thing hasn't quite lived up to his
potential as yet so let's wait and see
what he's got in store for us tomorrow
morning at the semi-finals and then if
that all goes well in the final later on
tomorrow night local time easily making
it through steady set of dives yeah very
impressive serve dives indeed good
effort by the Mexican and he is through
to the moment Chris Meers is an 18th
place he's got the last one I enrolled
is Rodriguez doesn't do something
spectacular should remain in 18th place
for two and a half somersaults two
twists Mike position for him
I finishes on a good one the young 18
year old from Venezuela I think he's had
a really good time today I've been
watching him in between dives smiling
away just taking in going wow I am in
the Olympic Games I'm doing what I love
to do I'm diving you know I'm not gonna
make it through maybe but I'm gonna give
it my all and that's exactly what
Rodriguez has done today it's only 1.40
and I think Chris Meers is gonna be just
about okay well not quite because if
this is around 74 Vendetti Mears is gone
for two-and-a-half somersaults to twist
pike 3.14 he misses entry as well
no his entry is spot-on but his arm
swing was all over the shop he nearly
missed his takeoff but his entry was
good Wow he's holding his head he knows
how close this is gonna be as well
cheers to bikes squares it up on the end
of the diving board completes the dive
it's a forward two and a half two twists
Wow I don't know which way this is going
to go it's going to be tough closest
either Benedetti
in or out Mia's in or out which way is
it going to go
and the newzeas benedetti has missed
down in 20th place the Italian got that
all wrong in terms of preparation and
that has opened the door for the home
favorite Chris Meers just and I mean
just to sneak into 18th place no place
for Jack lure the Chris Meers has made
it and that's the agonized face on
Mackay Leben deathy who knows he is not
returning the crowd I have seen the
score Wallace indeed you all do in just
a moment
big hug between coach and diver you
won't see it yet the crowd have seen it
on the scoreboard Chris it's going to be
better tomorrow mate but he's there
for what a competition that was just
getting our breasts back that was
extraordinary seen everything after
somebody god forbid hitting their head
on the diving or we've seen everything
in that competition it just shows the
heartbreak this is how much it means to
these athletes Mickey there didn't dive
as well as he won into today and just
ended up on the wrong side of that top
18 gutting for him fantastic news for
the other divers who have made it
through right then these are the ones
who will return top 18 pretty much all
the names you might expect although
there's only one Chinese at the top
there because of a bit of an aberration
by the other but he will return on page
2 Alexandre de Partie getting through in
ninth place for Canada to Americans
safely through Ching Kai - it will do
acting well great last diver hace Castro
Warren Kuznetsov trigger off and Chris
Meers qualifies by less than three
points in the end and the Malaysian
misses out as does bent deti but 18th
place crispy is for Great Britain and
all these I'll be thinking about what
they're going to do with the rest of
their week Jack law included of that
last ayah that went so wrong
Stefan feck bowing out after round three
what an extraordinary competition we
can't expect that kind I would I say
calamities but that kind of excitement
and a range of emotions surely in the
semi-final well I don't know let's see
e18 divers have made it through I'm very
surprised not to see Jack Lauper and I'm
sure he feels absolutely devastated me
as did a great job so did many of the
other divers there were some fantastic
dives but lots of things happen this is
what it's about
you've got to make it through the
polymer rounds you make it through but
then of course everything goes to zero
so it doesn't matter whether you're he
Chong or Chris Meers everyone starts at
zero in the semi-finals they've got to
get to bed tonight they've got to get
some sleep if they can and get up early
tomorrow morning to come in and train
because the competition starts 10:00
a.m. tomorrow morning local time
you better be with us you had better be
with us make a date record it do
whatever you want but don't be anywhere
else the semi-finals are gonna be great
and the final isn't evening to make sure
you rejoin Leon Taylor myself Bob Bala
thank you for joining us for an
extraordinary night of diving I'm sure
you'd agree good night
[Music]